[distant animal calls]
[eerie music playing]
[faint creaking]
[bugle fanfare playing]
Morning, gentlemen.
[horses whinnying]
-You Augustus Landor?
-I am.
And you?
Captain Hitchcock at your service.
Second-in-command at the Academy.
I'm here to inform you
Superintendent Thayer
requests an immediate audience.
-And the nature of this audience?
-I'll leave that to the colonel.
-When might this take place?
-At your earliest convenience.
[chuckles]
And if I should decide not to come?
That would be your own concern.
You're a private citizen.
[exhales deeply]
Well, it's a fine day for a ride.
[intriguing music playing]
[Thayer] The governor suggests
that you were a legend
among New York City constables.
And when he recommended your services,
he noted your impressive accomplishments,
including apprehending
the leaders of the Daybreak Boys,
breaking up the dreaded Shirt Tails gang,
and solving a particularly grisly murder
of a young prostitute in Elysian Fields.
Your talents include
code breaking, riot control,
and gloveless interrogation.
You're a minister's son from Gloucester
who came to New York
while still in your teens.
And you are a widower, Mr. Landor.
Three years now.
-[Hitchcock] Shall I send for coffee?
-[Landor] Beer will do nicely.
[bell tolling]
[exhales]
You, uh…
You keep these notes in a pigeonhole
back there somewhere, do you?
What else do they say?
Do they say that I haven't
darkened the door of a church
in a long time?
Does it mention
that my daughter ran off a while back?
We are aware
of your daughter's disappearance.
And we offer our sympathy.
With all due respect,
I hope I have not offended.
No. No, no, no.
No, sorry. I ought to apologize.
And I do. Please carry on.
Mr. Landor, we are obliged
to proceed with extreme discretion.
We're looking for someone.
A private citizen
of well-documented industry and tact
who might carry out inquiries
on the Academy's behalf.
Huh.
They're of a highly complex
and delicate nature
and concern one of our cadets.
Second-year man
from Kentucky by the name of Fry.
-Leroy Fry.
-There's no point in dancing around it.
Fry hanged himself… last night.
Oh.
Well, I'm sorry to hear that.
A dreadful business, this.
But you must understand our position.
We have been specifically charged
with the care of these young men,
to make them gentlemen and soldiers,
and to that end, we drive them.
But we'd like to think
we know when to… stop driving them.
A boy hangs himself…
uh, that's a matter for the coroner.
[Hitchcock] I'm afraid
that's not the end of it.
Cadet Fry's body was
violated last night in the hospital ward.
Violated? By whom?
Well, if we knew that, we would
have had no need to summon you.
I'm sure the Academy
has its share of pranksters.
This was no prank, Mr. Landor.
Leroy Fry's heart
was carved from his chest.
[somber music playing]
[Landor] Dr. Marquis, how does
a person go about doing this?
[Dr. Marquis] Scalpel. Or any good,
sharp knife would do.
But getting to the heart,
that's the tricky part.
Those gashes on the lungs and liver
came from angling
the blade to save the heart.
And how would one preserve the heart?
A container of some sort.
Wrapped in muslin, maybe, or newspaper.
Very likely surrounded by ice.
What type of fella could do this?
A strong one.
Not a woman, then?
No woman as I've ever had
the pleasure of meeting, no.
[Landor] What about his medical pedigree?
Would he need to be as well-educated
and well-trained as yourself?
Not necessarily.
He'd need a lot of light,
and know where to cut,
but it wouldn't have to be
a doctor or a surgeon.
-It'd have to be--
-A madman!
And still out there.
[drill sergeant] Port arms!
[Thayer] You'll have to forgive me,
Mr. Landor.
You've found us
in a very delicate position.
[drill sergeant] Left, face!
There are certain
powerful senators in Washington
who would like nothing more than
to see us fail utterly, to shut us down.
I'm asking you to help save the honor
of the United States Military Academy.
And save it, I'll try.
[pensive music playing]
[Landor] You were, uh, on guard duty
last night, Mr. Huntoon.
Yes, sir.
Post at 9:30. Relieved at midnight
and made my way back to the guardroom.
Where is that?
Number four, sir. By Fort Clinton.
I… I admit, I'm not very familiar
with the grounds,
but it seems that the part
we're standing on right now
is not on the way
from Fort Clinton to North Barracks.
-No, sir.
-Oh. What took you off course?
Well, sir, on my way, I heard something.
I reckoned it was an animal.
It sounded like it was dying
or caught in a trap, so I came to help.
I'm terribly partial to animals.
Uh… I was running this way
until I brushed Cadet Fry, sir.
-How'd he look?
-Not well, sir.
He wasn't hanging straight.
It was almost
as if he was seated in a chair.
I'm not following you.
Well, his feet were
touching the ground, sir.
-His feet were touching the ground?
-Yes, sir.
All right. What did you do next?
I ran. Ran straight back
to North Barracks.
Hmm.
Uh, one last question
and I'll trouble you no more.
Did you see anyone else about?
No, sir.
Mr. Huntoon.
[pensive music continues]
[Landor] The neck…
That's what first struck me.
See?
Not a clean cinch at all.
The rope grabbed at him
and ran up and down the neck
looking for purchase.
As though…
As though he was… fighting.
Hmm?
Look, if you would, at his fingers.
Blistered fresh
from clutching at the rope…
[door opens]
-…trying to peel the thing off him.
-[door closes]
May I ask what's going on here?
This is, uh, quite irregular.
I was wondering if you wouldn't mind
feeling around the back of Mr. Fry's head.
You did examine Mr. Fry?
Of course I examined him, as is my job.
[Landor] Hmm.
[Dr. Marquis softly] Haven't we already
been through this?
-Uh…
-Hmm.
There is a contusion of sort.
Parietal region.
Approximately three inches.
[breathes deeply]
-I must have missed that.
-Mmm.
[Hitchcock] Someone murdered Mr. Fry.
Is this what
you're telling us, Mr. Landor?
You might be onto something there,
Captain Hitchcock.
[bones crack]
[cracking]
Well, anyone
could have missed that, doctor.
Mr. Landor.
[soldiers marching nearby]
[door closes]
So now you're on board,
I think it's important
we set some ground rules.
You will report to me
on a daily basis and I to the colonel.
And you mustn't breathe a word of this
to anyone, inside or outside the Academy.
-Is that all?
-One final condition.
There will be no drinking throughout
the course of this investigation.
Your reputation precedes you.
[distant animal calls]
-[Landor sighs]
-[footsteps approaching]
[Landor grunts]
Oh.
Pardon.
-Are you Augustus Landor?
-[coughs] I am.
Unless I mistake, you've been
tasked with solving the mystery
surrounding Leroy Fry.
That's so. What might I do for you?
It is incumbent upon me
and the honor of this institution
to divulge some of the conclusions
which I have reached.
Conclusions?
Regarding the late Mr. Fry.
I'd be most interested.
The man you're looking for
is a poet.
[marching band playing]
[Landor] Private Cochrane.
When Leroy Fry's body
was brought back to the hospital,
you were detailed to guard it?
I was, sir.
-Did anything happen while on watch?
-Not till around 2:30.
-That's when I was relieved of my duty.
-Who relieved you?
-Private, who relieved you?
-I can't tell you, sir.
Only that it was an officer.
-He never identified himself?
-No, sir.
But I wouldn't expect it of an officer.
Hmm.
What did this officer say to you?
He said, "Thank you, private.
That will be all. I'm relieving you."
-An odd request, no?
-Yes, sir. Very.
-Did you see this officer's face?
-No, sir.
I had only a candle. It was terribly dark.
Right, tell me then,
how did you know it was an officer?
The bar on his shoulder, sir.
But I must admit, it was so very strange.
-How so?
-The bars.
The bars on his left shoulder
were missing.
[intriguing music playing]
[violin playing softly]
[door opens]
[door closes]
[Benny] Ah, there's the man himself.
Benny knows a man
who's in need of a drink when he sees one.
The very sight of it warms my blood.
-Benny!
-Sir.
-Here's… to rules.
-Fuck 'em.
Patsy.
Patsy!
What's grieving you?
Did you hear about that poor cadet?
-They say it took him hours to die.
-"They"?
Him.
Aren't you meant to be in recital?
Uh… Good evening. Recital?
No, I won't be missed.
They hardly know I'm at the Academy.
And besides, I've learned more
in rooms like this than any classroom.
I don't doubt it.
Sit, please. Please, sit. Have a… Have a…
-Seat?
-Seat. Thank you. Uh…
Fourth Classman Poe. E. A. Poe.
Edgar A. Poe.
Worked up quite a thirst, I see.
Helps take the bite off the gloom.
Um…
So tell me, how did you learn
about Leroy Fry?
Uh, well, from Huntoon, of course.
He has been spouting the news
like the town crier. [chuckles softly]
Perhaps someone
might hang him before too long.
You don't mean to imply
that someone hanged Mr. Fry?
I don't mean to imply anything.
Why do you think that the man
who cut Leroy Fry's heart out
was a poet?
Well…
The heart is a symbol or it is nothing.
Now take away the symbol
and what do you have?
It's a fistful of muscle of no more
aesthetic interest than a bladder.
Now, to remove a man's heart
is to traffic in symbol.
And who better equipped for such labor
than a poet?
Awfully literal-minded poet,
it would seem--
Oh, you cannot pretend
that this act of savagery
did not startle the literary resonances
from the very crevices of your mind.
Lord Suckling's charming song,
"I prithee send me back my heart
Since I cannot have thine"
Or… Or the Bible even,
"Create in me a clean heart, O God."
"A broken and a contrite heart
thou wilt not despise."
Then we might just as easily
be seeking a religious maniac.
No, you see, I neglected
to tell you that I am a poet myself,
hence inclined to think as one.
[exhales heavily]
I don't get around to poetry much.
Why should you? You're an American.
And you?
An artist.
That is to say, without country.
-Oh… [laughing]
-What, Mr. Landor?
You've been a great help.
You want a second look
at a cadet named Loughborough.
In former days, Leroy Fry's roommate,
until they had a falling out.
The nature of which remains uncertain.
[unsettling music playing]
[Hitchcock] Mr. Loughborough.
Tell Mr. Landor
how you were acquainted with Mr. Fry.
Yes, sir. We were roommates.
Hmm.
You ever have a falling out?
I wouldn't call it a falling out. Just…
a matter of diverging paths, sir.
-What made you diverge?
-Well…
Nothing so…
A matter of course.
[sternly] If you know of anything
pertaining to Mr. Fry,
you're bound to disclose it at once.
Well, it's like this, sir.
I'd say he'd fallen in with
a bad bunch.
At least that's what he called them.
[Landor] Now then, tell me,
by "bad bunch,"
did he mean other cadets?
[Loughborough] He never said,
but I assumed so.
And why didn't you come forward earlier?
I didn't quite see
that it had any bearing,
happening so long ago, sir.
Dismissed.
Mr. Stoddard.
You were the last one
to see Mr. Fry alive.
Yes, sir.
-Speak up.
-I'm just a bit ill, sir.
[clears throat] I did see Leroy
late on the night in question.
Passed him on the way
to barracks as I was coming in.
You spoke to him?
He stopped me,
asking if any officers were about.
How did Mr. Fry look?
It was so very dark.
I… I wouldn't trust my memory.
Did you see anything
on his person, a length of rope, maybe?
-None that I could see.
-Hmm.
There was something. Uh…
As Fry was leaving, I did ask
where he was off to at such an hour.
And?
He said, "Necessary business."
What did you take that to mean?
I don't know.
-[Landor clears throat]
-Dismissed.
-[cadet] Pardon me, captain.
-Yes.
Christ almighty.
"A cow and sheep have been
murdered and mutilated in Cold Spring."
"Their chests most cruelly carved open
and their hearts removed."
Are any of God's creatures
immune from this man?
We don't know that this is the same man.
What?
Coincidence, is it?
Effective 0600 tomorrow morning,
all men will only attend
class, meals, prayer services.
Nothing more!
[Landor] If any of your classmates ask,
we did nothing more than discuss
your acquaintance with Leroy Fry.
[Poe] There was no acquaintance.
I never knew him.
-[Landor] What?
-I never knew the fellow.
-[Landor] Then I misunderstood you.
-Huh. You're not the first.
So, if this is not a discussion,
what is it?
An offer of employment.
There's no pay.
None of your classmates
may know what you're doing
until long after you're done with it.
If they do find out,
they'll likely curse your name.
Oh! An irresistible offer.
[chuckles dryly]
No, um, please, tell me more.
Excellent. I need you to decipher this…
This segment of a larger note.
You'll have to work secretly
and as precisely as you can.
[melancholy music playing]
[melancholy music continues]
[knocking at door]
I am pleased to report
I have successfully decoded your message.
Hmm. Handwritten,
it is of a personal nature.
Fry had it with him
at the time of his death.
From that,
we may presume it was sufficient
to draw him from his barracks
on the night in question.
As the rest of the message
was torn from his hand,
we may presume that the note,
in some way, identified its sender.
Now the use
of rather primitive black capitals
would also indicate that the sender
wished to disguise his identity.
An invitation of sorts, or might we
more accurately call it a trap. [claps]
A trap?
Hmm.
-Now, with that in mind… Oh, may I?
-Mmm-hmm.
Let's concentrate
our labors on the third line
which we know, for a fact, is complete.
"Be." But be what?
Something that begins with "L."
"Little"? "Lucky"?
No. Neither gibes with the invitation.
"Be lost"?
No. No. Too ungainly a construction.
If in fact Leroy Fry's attendance was
desired at a particular time and place,
there is but one word, "late."
"Be late."
And as we scan the third line,
the first word becomes almost
insultingly simple to deduce, "don't."
So, "Don't be late."
Now, look closely, Mr. Landor.
We need not journey far
for a suitable candidate.
If Fry is going
to a predetermined location,
he was, from the perspective
of the writer, coming.
So, "Come, Mr. Fry."
Now, with that in place,
it is the height of simplicity
to deduce the next word.
Can it be any other than "soon"?
We insert the word, et voilà!
"Don't be late. Come soon."
And there you have it,
the solution to our petite énigme
-respectfully submitted.
-Mmm-hmm.
First-rate work. I thank you.
-Just one thing.
-Yes?
Did you have any luck
with the first two lines?
Well, I was forced to declare them a loss.
Are you a good speller?
Oh, flawless. Judged so
by no less an authority
than the Reverend John Bransby
of Stoke Newington.
So I take it that you've never done
what so many of… us do.
Misspell similar sounding words.
For example,
"they're," "their," and "there."
A common solecism.
An invitation indeed. "Meet me there."
Of course, we still don't know
where to meet, do we?
Something with "N-G" trailing behind.
The landing!
-And might I add, the cove by the landing.
-Excellent choice.
So, "I'll be at the cove by the landing."
"Meet me there at say, 11:00 p.m. or so."
So, "Don't be late. Come see me."
Might be closer to the mark.
-[Poe] Yeah.
-Ah…
Does this suggest anything to you?
Why would he meet
a fellow cadet at the landing
-when you can meet him anywhere?
-Hmm.
Because it's not a cadet, but a woman.
[Landor] Hmm.
You knew the solution
all along, Mr. Landor.
I had an idea.
Well, if this is indeed a woman we seek,
I believe I may be credited
with a sighting of her.
The morning after Leroy Fry's death,
before I knew anything of what had passed,
I awoke, and began speaking
the opening lines of a poem,
lines that speak of a mysterious woman
in profound distress.
Then, just outside the mess,
appears the most beautiful creature
I've ever had the pleasure
of laying eyes on.
[Landor] Who was she?
I haven't the faintest.
But why do you believe that this poem
or young woman are connected with Mr. Fry?
The air of concealed violence.
Unspeakable duress.
An unknown woman.
You could have woken
any morning and written this.
But I didn't write it. It was dictated.
-Dictated?
-Mmm-hmm.
By whom?
My mother.
She's dead.
Dead nearly, uh, 20 years.
[Landor] Tell me about this Poe fella.
Oh, Poe, he…
A lovely boy.
Beautiful manners. Um… Talks a lot.
Definitely. And definitely
something peculiar about him.
[chuckling] Because he talks a lot?
No, because he's filled
with senseless fantasies.
Tells me about a poem,
claims it has something
to do with Leroy Fry's death.
Claims it was dictated to him
in his sleep by his dead mother.
You of all people know
that the people we lost…
are always with us.
Man will do most anything
to cheat death, won't he?
[pensive music playing]
[creaking]
[Dr. Marquis] A container of some sort.
Wrapped in muslin, maybe, or newspaper.
Very likely surrounded by ice.
[pensive music continues]
[music swells]
[lock clicks]
[creaking]
[music fades]
[water trickling]
[floorboard creaking]
-[pigeons cooing]
-[wings fluttering]
[hollow thump]
[hollow thudding]
[unsettling music building]
[foot scraping]
[unsettling music continues]
[footsteps approaching]
Good. My note reached you.
-Were you followed?
-Followed?
How unprofessional. Certainly not.
-What is this?
-The scene of the crime.
The second… crime.
Where Fry's heart was brought.
You mentioned the taking
of Fry's heart drew you to the Bible.
I must admit.
I was already moving in that direction.
Not to the Bible.
But to religion.
This… This does appear to render
a ceremony of some sort.
Blood and candles placed
in an intentional manner.
-A circle.
-Mmm. And a triangle.
And Fry's heart very likely placed inside.
I have an old friend
who might be of some use.
[pensive music playing]
[Landor] Professor Jean Pépé
is an expert in symbols…
-[Landor] Pépé!
-…rituals…
[knocking at door]
-…the occult.
-Professor!
[Landor] Pépé might be
-the most peculiar man…
-[Pépé] Come in. I'm back here.
-[Landor] Sorry to intrude.
-…I've had the pleasure of coming across.
[Landor] I, uh, bring something curious
I would like you to observe.
[Pépé] Uh…
This can only be a magic circle.
I remember seeing it in
Le Véritable Dragon Rouge.
And if I recall all right,
the magician would stand there
in the triangle.
Alone?
Well, he might have
a group of assistants.
And candles and torches
on either side, light everywhere,
a festival of light, in fact.
Now, Gus, if you go to the third shelf…
On the second to the top.
That volume on the top.
Yes. Yes.
Pierre de Lancre,
redoubtable witch hunter.
-You read French, Mr. Poe?
-Well, yes.
Please read in silence.
It's in the center page.
De Lancre executed 600 Basque witches
and left behind
the remarkable volume you now peruse.
But the book I wish to give you,
Discours du Diable by Henri Le Clerc,
who executed 700 witches
before he was done,
is reputed to have been destroyed.
Now, rumor has it that he left behind
two or three other volumes
identical to the one destroyed.
Now, finding one has become
the idée fixe of many an occult collector.
-Why?
-Why? Ooh… [chuckles]
Le Clerc left behind instructions
for securing…
immortality.
[Poe] Oh, my Lord.
"It is commonly known
among the fraternity of evil angels
that the contents
of a witch's sabbath feast
are confined to the following sundries."
"Unclean animals such as are
never eaten by Christian peoples,
the hearts of unbaptized children,
and the hearts of hanged men."
[drum roll]
[Landor] I need you
to discretely infiltrate the cadets,
see if you can ferret out which of them
may have a connection to the occult.
[Lee] Explain yourself.
Well, um, certain overtures
have been made to me,
rather dark, and shall I say,
unchristian overtures.
-Unchristian?
-Yes.
I've been spurred to question
the very grounds of my faith.
And to dabble in mysterious and arcane
practices of an ancient provenance.
-Arcane practices?
-He means black magic. Who was it?
[clears throat] I demand to know.
[Poe] I'm honor bound
not to reveal his name.
[Lee] Who was it?
You can't drag it from me,
not if God himself threatened
to smite me with a lightning bolt.
-If you want to join our prayers--
-No, I gave my word.
-One asks you to question your faith--
-It must stay private.
Was it Marquis?
Hamilton, watch yourself.
[Poe] Yes, I have a name,
but I need a face to go with it.
-[Dr. Marquis] Vertigo, hmm?
-Mmm.
Well, things are swirling about.
Your heart rate is rather quick.
Very well, Mr. Poe,
keep to the house today
and take care of yourself.
Present this to Lieutenant Locke
and his cadet commandeer,
Artemus, my son.
He'll make sure
you're relieved of your duties.
[Locke] You wish to be excused
from class because you were feeling
vertiginous?
And an even worse ailment not noted.
A grand ennui seizure.
"Grand ennui"?
Of a most pronounced character.
Mind yourself, Poe.
You may ask the doctor yourself.
It's true, Lieutenant.
My father did tell me
he's never seen anything quite like it.
Very well.
But I am charging you
with unbecoming brazenness.
Three demerits.
Return at once to your quarters.
And you would best be there when
the officers come around for inspection.
[drill sergeant shouting commands]
-Poe, is it?
-Yes.
Artemus Marquis.
I must say, your brazenness is admirable.
Tonight, eleven o'clock.
18 North Barracks.
[Poe] Apologies for my tardiness.
I hope I haven't kept you too long.
This is lovely.
[gasps] Books!
You have never interested me more.
Where to begin? Oh…
The lamentable Fenimore Cooper.
I guess every library must have one.
Ooh, what a collection.
History of Egypt, and all sorts.
You've been found out.
Oh?
You gave me to understand
you didn't read poetry.
I don't.
Byron!
-A personal favorite, Mr. Landor…
-Please.
…and might I say, terribly well-thumbed.
That's my daughter's.
[clears throat]
And your daughter is no longer here?
No. No, she ran off with someone.
Someone you knew?
In passing.
And she's never to return?
Not likely.
Then we're both alone in this world.
But you have your mother.
She still speaks to you.
-At any rate.
-[chuckling] Yes.
Yes, from time to time.
And I might add, whatever's good in me,
in person, in spirit, comes from her.
Your daughter. What's her name?
If you don't object.
Mathilde.
Mattie.
You needn't say anymore, Mr. Landor.
-So you say you found something.
-Well, no. Better than that.
Someone goes by the name Marquis.
The doctor.
No. His son, Artemus.
And I have tasked myself with maneuvering
into his impenetrable peer group.
[door opens]
[Stoddard] Here's another
good creature of God.
Courtesy of la divine Patsy.
[Ballinger] Are you going to report us
for defying curfew, Poe?
Do our wee transgressions offend thee?
Not only am I not offended,
Mr. Ballinger, but, mmm…
another round is in order.
[Artemus chuckles]
[Ballinger] Drink it.
All of it, woman.
[Stoddard] Ballinger, you really
are quite the bully tonight.
[Poe] Mmm.
Another, s'il vous plaît.
Oh, I thank you.
Mmm.
-I can do this all night.
-[Artemus] Uh-uh.
Easy, Ballinger.
I've gone to great trouble
to secure that mash.
Poe.
I understand you're a published poet.
I am told I evidence a humble gift.
[chuckles] Well, then I demand
a public reading.
-Pleasure us.
-Oh. [chuckles]
I met a lewd nude in Bermuda
Who thought she was shrewd
I was shrewder
She thought it quite crude
To be wooed in the nude
I pursued her
Subdued her and screwed her
-[laughing]
-Well done, Poe.
Bravo.
Losing card… is a seven.
Winning card… is a jack.
Oh!
[Artemus] Well, well, well.
It's your lucky day, Poe.
Thank you.
Is it true, Poe, that Detective Landor
interrogated you about Fry?
He was mistakenly under the impression
that I was an intimate of Fry's.
Were you?
I was not.
Fitting that the only thing
that Fry could do to gain attention
was to hang himself.
[Stoddard] I think he hanged himself
in despair over being jilted by a lady.
[Lee] And what lady
might that be, Stoddard?
[Ballinger] What of your sister, Artemus?
Didn't she dazzle Fry?
[Artemus] Oh, come now, Randy.
You were closer to Fry
than anyone in this room.
I don't believe
I was so near to him… [inhales]
…as you.
[chuckles]
All right. Where were we?
[bell tolling in distance]
Halt!
Curfew not apply to you, Mr. Poe?
Explain yourself.
Candles were
to be extinguished three hours ago.
[clears throat] I'm sorry, sir.
Your apologies have always
rung hollow with me.
Leroy Fry met his maker
when he too was out after curfew.
Return to barracks at once.
You're lucky you're not
digging your own grave.
Thank you, sir.
Pick up the pace.
[soft scraping]
[Mathilde muttering indistinctly]
[muttering continues]
[sniffles]
[whispers] Mattie?
[exhales shakily]
[wardrobe opens]
[sighs softly]
[melancholy music playing]
[sobbing]
[sniffling]
[melancholy music continues]
[imperceptible]
[sniffles]
[music fades]
[priest] "Remember thou me
for thy goodness' sake, O Lord."
"For in death
there is no remembrance of thee,
in thy grave who shall give thee thanks?"
"According to thy mercy,
remember thou me
for thy goodness' sake, O Lord."
"Mine eye is consumed because of grief."
You're Mr. Landor. Aren't you?
I am.
[sniffles] I'm Leroy's mother.
I'd like you to have this. [sniffles]
Leroy's diary.
It goes back at least three years.
I don't recall…
I'm sorry.
Terrible loss.
I don't recall any diary
being found with his personal effects.
It was Mr. Ballinger who sent it to me.
-Mr. Ballinger?
-Yes.
As soon as he heard what had happened,
he went straight to Leroy's quarters
to see what could be done.
The dear boy mailed it to me. [sobs]
I see.
And just now… as soon as he saw me,
he said, "I thought you should have
Leroy's diary with you in Kentucky."
"And if you feel like burning it,
go right ahead."
How considerate of him.
But I can make no sense of it.
All the numbers and letters…
But… seeing how the Army
is depending on you,
it seems only right
that you should have it.
[pensive music playing]
[Julia] I'll be back to meet you
all the time.
-To manage her needs…
-[Dr. Marquis] I understand.
…'cause all of us are in this together.
[Landor] Doctor!
[Dr. Marquis] Ah, Mr. Landor.
What a pleasant surprise.
Uh, please, let me introduce you
to my wife, Julia.
I've heard so much about you.
It's a pleasure.
Aren't you the gentleman
inquiring after Mr. Fry's death?
I am.
Well, we were just discussing the matter.
Indeed, my husband informs me
that despite his own heroic efforts,
the body of Mr. Fry had been judged
too far along for public display.
Hmm.
His poor parents.
Oh. Indeed.
Well, this whole matter has shaken us.
Be assured, I won't rest
until we've apprehended him.
Lovely to make your acquaintance.
My dear.
I understand you're a widower, Mr. Landor.
That is so.
Well, all due sympathy.
Was it recent?
Your wife going to her reward?
Two years ago now.
Only a few months
after we moved to the Highlands.
A sudden illness, was it?
Not sudden…
enough.
Well, your sacrifices aren't lost on me.
-Condolences.
-Thank you.
[Julia] Hmm.
-[piano playing]
-[wind whistling]
Brava.
Edgar, did I not tell you
my sister is a prodigy?
Marvelous, my dear.
Brought a tear to my eye.
[Poe] Yeah.
A lovely run, Miss Marquis.
-Truly.
-Yes.
Your immortality is assured.
I can't think of any woman
who wishes to be immortal, Randy.
I am at once reminded
of Sir Thomas Grey's,
"Full many a flower
Is born to blush unseen"
"And waste its sweetness
On the desert air"
A favorite, Mr. Poe.
And what do you think
of my little protégé?
I think Mr. Poe is far beyond
being anyone's protégé.
He's certainly not to be corrupted
by the likes of you.
[cadets chuckle]
[Julia] All right, Lea.
That's enough now.
You need to rest before dinner.
-[coughs] If you'll excuse me, gentlemen.
-[Ballinger] Thank you, Lea.
[Artemus] Randy, chairs.
Stoddard, come on, man. Chess board.
All right. I'm bored now.
[Julia] I don't care! She's ill.
In her condition,
she shouldn't be entertaining at all.
[Poe] Miss Marquis.
Oh, um… Pardon me.
Nothing would afford me greater pleasure
than an audience with you on Saturday.
I'm sure that's true, Mr. Poe,
but… I'm afraid I'm engaged Saturday.
Ah, I see.
[in French]
Your coat and your hat, sir.
Thank you, Eugenia. You needn't have.
I could have fetched my coat myself.
-Good evening.
You speak French, Mr. Poe.
With an accent that is rather charming.
[in English] So you propose this Saturday?
Or Sunday, if that's preferable.
Or Monday, even.
And where do you propose this audience?
Let me guess.
Gee's Point? Flirtation Walk?
Oh, no, no, no.
Neither, I'm afraid, no.
I had in mind the cemetery.
-The cemetery?
-Mmm.
How interesting.
Yes, I certainly think so.
Well, I wish you good evening.
[intriguing music playing]
[door closes]
[Lea] It's all so bare now.
But to enjoy the Highlands
in the full extent of their glory,
it must be seen immediately
after the fall of the leaf.
Why is that?
Vegetation does not improve,
but rather obstructs
God's originating design.
A romantic.
You do enjoy talking
about God and death, don't you?
I do consider death
to be poetry's most exalted theme.
[coughing]
Shall we?
-A lovely spot.
-[sighs] Yes, it's my favorite.
How well it sits on you, morbidity.
Suits you better than your uniform.
The only one to match you is Artemus.
I've never seen him dwell
in the realms of melancholy.
He does consent
to visit our world for long intervals.
[Lea] You know I believe it's possible
to dance on broken glass
for some length of time.
Not forever.
Yes, I can see you two
hold much in common.
[coughing]
I hope you aren't cold.
[unsettling music playing]
The frigid climate
has clearly settled in for good.
Please, let us not.
Do not suppose I came here
to talk about the weather. How prosaic.
I'm sorry.
My sole concern was for your welfare.
Proceed then, by all means.
Declare your undying love, so we may
both return home and be none the worse.
-I was just saying--
-I'm sorry.
Sorry, I'm being a horror,
and I have no idea why.
You are cold.
Miss Marquis, would you
like to borrow my cloak?
-Quite all right.
-It's really no, um…
I…
[gulps]
-What?
-Miss Marquis.
-Lea! Lea!
-[whimpering]
[music crescendoes]
[choking]
Lea! Lea? What's happening?
Lea!
Lea.
[choking stops]
[breathing deeply]
My God, Lea.
Are you all right?
-Lea?
-I'm rather fine.
[Poe] Are you sure you're all right?
I was quite terrified.
[Lea] It happens.
It's nothing to worry about.
Your, um…
Your spirit so emboldens me
that I feel free to confess…
my mother has
a kind of presence in my life.
My sleepings and my awakenings.
Yes. Yes.
At times, I believe the dead haunt us
because we love them too little.
We forget them, you see.
We don't mean to, but we do.
I believe they feel most cruelly deserted,
and so they clamor for us.
Perhaps it best we don't give
that too much thought.
I want you to know how grateful I was…
to open my eyes and find you there.
To look deep within you
and find something
I would never have expected.
Not in a thousand years.
Thank you.
[animals howling]
[rustling]
[howling continues]
[Poe grunts]
-[man grunting]
-[Poe groaning]
[coughing]
[choking]
[groans] Stop!
[grunts]
[gasping, panting]
[groaning]
Bastards ought to know
their fucking place.
-[Poe groaning]
-[Ballinger] Stay away from Lea.
[Landor grunts]
Leave off!
-[Ballinger grunts]
-[Poe groaning]
[Landor grunts]
Leave off, Ballinger!
Or you will be court-martialed!
[Poe groans]
[Ballinger] Ugly fuck.
[Landor] You all right?
Clearly that savage knows
that Lea prefers me to him.
-And if he seeks to frighten me away--
-Frighten?
-He looked set on killing you.
-Killing me? Oh!
Oh, no. Before I let him come
between me and my heart's desire,
I will kill him.
It's always been this way.
People underestimating me.
Friends, classmates,
my very own benefactor.
-Thank you, Patsy.
-Everyone.
Everyone…
but my dear mother.
And thank you for assisting earlier.
It's unlike me to be caught by surprise.
And you surprise too. Don't you, Landor?
I have no desire to offend,
but you're much more sophisticated
than you present.
[chuckles] Now, tell me, is it true
you once solicited a confession
with nothing more than a piercing look?
[chuckles]
With enough patience,
the suspect will often
interrogate himself.
Well, you are most
delightful company, Landor.
I shall write a poem someday.
Something that shall send
your name down through the ages.
[Patsy] Even after this attack,
you don't suspect Randy Ballinger?
So where does this leave you?
Your investigation.
I'm interested in Artemus Marquis.
I take it you know him?
Well, who doesn't?
Glorious look to him.
He'd almost have
to die young, wouldn't he?
But I wouldn't have
picked him for the violent sort.
Always, um, very cool.
[Landor] Perhaps he's not our man.
There's a quality to him.
To his entire family.
They act like people
who are guilty of something.
Aren't all families guilty of something?
[knocking at door]
-Captain.
-It's Mr. Ballinger.
I'm afraid he's gone missing.
[dramatic music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[cadet 1] Next to those rocks.
[cadet 2] Here on this side too.
[cadet 3] Up the hill.
[cadet 4] Cadet, right side.
Behind those trees.
[cadet 5] Nothing here.
[indistinct chatter continues]
[Lee] Captain! Up here!
[Hitchcock] My Lord.
[Dr. Marquis] Mr. Ballinger's dissection
wasn't as clean as Fry's.
Suggesting it was performed
by different hands.
As for the castration…
[hesitates] Well, I'm…
[Thayer] Castration?
My God, Landor.
We're no closer to finding
who's responsible for this
than we were a month ago!
We are closer.
-It's only a matter of time.
-Tell me!
Have you found
more evidence of satanic practices?
What of the so-called officer
who persuaded Private Cochrane
to abandon Leroy Fry's body?
Or Fry's diary?
Have you found a single clue
that might be of use?
A maniac is freely roaming these hills,
disemboweling my men.
Men who barely carry out their duties,
hardly leave their barracks or sleep.
And if they can sleep,
do so with their muskets!
[scoffs]
I'm beginning to believe
you no longer think I'm competent
to undertake this investigation.
Thank you, doctor.
It's not your competence we question,
it's your allegiance.
Is there any possibility that this
could have been the work of Mr. Poe?
Poe?
Just yesterday,
he was regaling his table mates
with an heroic account
of his epic tussle with Mr. Ballinger,
declaring that he
fully intended to kill him
should they ever cross swords again.
You've seen Poe.
Can you honestly tell me
he subdued Ballinger?
No, there would have been no need.
Firearm would have turned the trick.
Whatever his relations with Ballinger,
there's no sign of any link
between Poe and Leroy Fry.
-They didn't even know each other.
-[Thayer] Oh, but they did.
They had a tussle
of their own last summer.
I don't suppose he ever volunteered
that bit of information, did he?
[pensive music building]
Then arrest him.
Arrest him if you are so persuaded.
All we have is motive.
We're looking to you to supply evidence!
Mr. Landor, do you harbor
a latent hostility toward this Academy?
Is that it?
I am risking my life
on behalf of your precious institution.
But yes.
I do believe that the Academy
takes away a young man's will.
It fences him with regulations and rules.
Deprives him of reason.
It makes him less human.
Are you implying
the Academy is to blame for these deaths?
Someone connected to the Academy, yes.
Hence, the Academy itself.
[Hitchcock] Well, that's absurd.
By your standard,
every crime committed
by a Christian will be a stain on Christ.
And so it is.
[pensive music continues]
[music fades]
When I first asked you… to take this job,
you told me you never
had dealings with Leroy Fry, so, uh…
Let's start there. Well?
-Well, that's not entirely true--
-Well… Well… Well…
Why is nothing simple with you, Poe?
Where are the facts?
Where are the simple facts?
Yes! Or no!
The truth!
-Did you know Leroy Fry?
-Yes.
Did you have words with Leroy Fry?
Yes. Yes.
Did you kill Leroy Fry?
Did you kill Randolph Ballinger?
[softly] No.
[exhales]
Did you have anything to do
with the desecrating of their bodies?
-No, no, no. May I be struck dead if I--
-But you do not deny
that you threatened both men?
Well, as it relates
to Ballinger, that was…
I never meant it.
-And Fry?
-I never once threatened him. I merely--
There is
a very disturbing pattern here, Poe.
Men who cross you
end up on the wrong end of a noose
with rather important organs
carved from their chests.
Mr. Landor…
[sighs deeply]
If I were to kill every cadet
who had abused me
during my brief tenure here,
I'm afraid you would find
the Corp of Cadets
reduced to less than a dozen.
Now, if you must know,
I've been a figure of fun
from my very first day here.
My manner, my age, my person…
my aesthetics.
If I had a thousand lifetimes,
I could not begin
to address all the injuries
that have been done to me.
Yes, I am guilty of a great,
great many things, but never that.
Never murder.
Now do you believe me?
I believe that you should take better care
of what you say and do.
For now, I can probably
hold off Hitchcock.
But if you ever lie to me again,
they can clap you in irons
and I won't lift a finger to help you.
Do you understand me?
Now if you'll excuse me,
I'm expected for dinner.
[exhales]
Thank you for joining us
in mourning Randolph's untimely passing.
The dear boy was family.
Don't you find my son
exceptionally handsome, Mr. Landor?
Um…
I would judge both of your children
to have been blessed in that regard.
[Julia] Yes, we are hereditarily blessed.
But I must say, I do find you a rarity.
A person of exceptional intelligence.
The quality in such
ridiculously short supply here.
[Artemus] And with that intelligence,
Mr. Landor,
I hope when you're finished
with your official business,
you will assist me
with a puzzle of my own.
-Oh, a puzzle?
-The strangest affair.
While in recital, Monday,
it appears someone
had rifled through my belongings.
-[Landor] Oh.
-[Dr. Marquis] Well, eh…
-Terrible people are abroad.
-Really, Father?
I was inclining toward the theory
that the fellow was simply rude,
while, of course,
having no idea who he was.
All the same,
you must be careful, Artemus.
-You really must.
-Oh, Mother.
It was probably
just some tiresome old fellow
with nothing better to do
and no life of his own to speak of.
A rustic sort of cottager.
Don't you think, Mr. Landor?
Oh.
-You have a cottage, don't you?
-Artemus.
You may even have some
very near relations who fit the pattern.
Perhaps a dear friend who likes
a tipple and to drink in a tavern.
Stop it! Just, please! I hate it!
I positively hate it
when you take on like this.
-I don't follow your drift, Mother.
-Oh, no, I'm sure you don't.
I might drift clear to the other side
of the Hudson and no one would care.
No one would follow!
-Would they, Daniel?
-[Dr. Marquis] Son, please.
[sobbing]
[door slams]
You'll… have to forgive my wife.
Mr. Ballinger's death
has cast a pall
over our happy little clan.
I wonder if you'd care
to join me in my study, Mr. Landor?
I'd be delighted.
[Dr. Marquis] My apologies, constable.
Living on pins and needles
has taken its toll on all of us.
-No need to apologize.
-[chuckles softly] Yeah.
And the time of year,
all this confinement…
Mmm. It is all very understandable.
I couldn't help noticing, doctor.
Is your daughter unwell?
Quite observant.
Yes.
Yes, she's…
She's had a rough go of it, that one.
Since she was a pup, really.
A ghastly illness
seizing her when no one is looking,
stopping her brain
and shaking her like a gourd.
Beautiful child.
One marked for marriage, status, children.
And in the same stroke, illness.
[piano playing faintly outside]
'Tis dreadful.
[door opens]
Gentlemen, Lea is in fine form
if you'd join us.
Thank you, son.
Shall we?
If you don't mind,
I'll just step out for some fresh air.
Of course.
[piano continues playing]
[Artemus] Father, have a game with me.
[Dr. Marquis]
Shall I try the scholars again
or something more challenging this time?
[piano music continues]
[indistinct conversation]
[faint piano music continues]
[music ends]
-Just remarkable.
-Hardly.
Passable, maybe.
You don't realize the effect
your playing has on me.
On all of us, really, I…
-Yes?
-Well, I…
I don't quite know how else to put it,
but, um… I've come to realize
that I would do most anything for you.
Oh, Edgar.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Julia] May I help you
find something, Mr. Landor?
You've recovered. And so soon.
Well, do forgive me.
I feared I was coming down with
one of those horrid migraines,
but it seems a moment's rest
was all I required.
And I feel quite cured. Mmm.
Let's put that dreadful,
old thing away, shall we?
I'm quite sure it won't fit you.
The good doctor and I
were in search of it.
And I found it.
[Julia] Look what the constable
found in our closet, darling.
Remember Artemus wearing it
as a young lad around the house?
Remember, love?
-I remember, Mother.
-It's my brother's coat.
Your brother's?
That's the only thing
we have to remember him by.
-[knocking on door]
-Why do you have it?
Perhaps Artemus can answer that.
[door opens and closes]
[Eugenia] Everyone is in the salon.
[Dr. Marquis] Ethan.
What brings you here?
Another cadet is missing.
And I've formed a search party
ready to go within the hour.
No stone will be left unturned.
[Thayer] God help us. I shudder to think--
[Landor] Gentlemen!
I've just been to Mr. Stoddard's quarters.
His trunk was empty. No civilian clothes
were to be found anywhere.
I believe he has run off.
Run off?
Fry's diary allows
that both Stoddard and Ballinger
were good mates with Leroy Fry.
Fearing he might be next, I think he ran.
Well, that may well be, but what about
Artemus and the officer's coat?
If he's involved, how can
we possibly delay arresting him?
He is… too cool a customer for that.
All he has to do is deny it.
Now, there's a last avenue
of inquiry I'm exploring.
Two of his closest companions are dead,
and imminently, I must report
to the president that we have our man.
We have our man, Landor. Do we not?
[dramatic music playing]
[Eugenia] Mademoiselle.
Edgar.
-[Poe] I, uh…
-[Landor] Professor?
Pépé?
Last time I was here,
you mentioned a witch hunter and a book.
Yes. Discours du Diable.
Henri Le Clerc.
Was Le Clerc a priest?
One burned at the stake.
[Poe] It came to me while I slept
Down, down, down
Came the hot threshing flurry
Ill at heart, I beseeched her to hurry
"Lenore"
She forbore the reply
Endless night
Caught her then in its slurry
Shrouding all, but her pale blue eye
Darkest night, black with hell
Charneled fury
Leaving only
That deathly blue eye
Do you see?
Lenore.
Lea.
It speaks of your unspeakable distress.
A conclusion to what's… oppressing you.
The poem…
is speaking to us.
Remember when you said
you'd do anything for me?
Your devil worshipper.
-Thank you, Pépé.
-Yeah.
[footsteps approaching]
Mr. Landor.
Your family.
Your family… have been
quite a puzzle.
I could never get a fix
of who was in command.
One time or other I suspected each of you.
It never occurred to me
that it might be someone
who wasn't even alive.
[voice shaking] Pardon me?
Father Henri Le Clerc.
Finest of witch hunters,
until he became the hunted.
What are you talking about?
Your daughter, she suffers
from a falling sickness, does she not?
She copes because
she is in contact with someone.
Someone who instructs her.
Him.
Do not make me question
your sanity, Mr. Landor.
Uh, what are you suggesting?
Le Clerc's incredibly rare
Discours du Diable.
Well, communicating with the devil
is not a pastime
with which I am familiar, Mr. Landor.
[hesitating]
I have never read a page of this book.
Does your daughter speak with the dead?!
[somber music playing]
Over the years, the seizures
have gotten much, much worse.
I…
I have tried
every medical regimen I could think of.
She was given three months to live.
Do you know
what it feels like to go to sleep,
not knowing if your daughter
will make it through the night?
But then, one day she came to me,
and said that she'd met someone.
Her great-great-grandfather.
Le Clerc?
Henri Le Clerc wasn't evil.
He… He was misunderstood.
[whispering indistinctly]
[Lea breathing deeply]
[speaking Latin]
They swore to me Mr. Fry was already dead.
They swore they could never kill anyone.
You believed them.
I had no choice.
You are a physician! A man of science!
How dare you
put your faith in such madness?
Because…
Because I… I… I couldn't save her myself.
My own art had failed me.
I sacrificed everything for my Lea.
So how can I then object
to her finding a cure elsewhere?
Doctor.
Communicating with the dead…
that's not normal. But murder…
destroying innocent lives…
that's inhuman.
Someone has to hang for this.
[coughing]
[hesitating]
I only indulged her because… miraculously,
she seemed to improve.
Doctor, where is your family?
Where are your children?
Mr. Poe was here earlier.
He left with… With Artemus.
Why is his cloak still in the hall?
Doctor, where is Lea?
Doctor, where is your family?
[dramatic musical flourish]
-[Lea breathing deeply]
-[Artemus] It's starting to wear off.
[Julia] Lea.
Continue.
[Julia speaking Latin]
[unsettling music playing]
[continues speaking Latin]
[Poe groans]
[Poe] What's happening?
It won't be much longer.
I don't feel terribly well.
-I thought…
-No. [shushing]
Just a few minutes more and I'll be free.
Free?
Yes.
Please, Lea. I'm…
This must happen.
You do understand.
Sacrifice is
the ultimate expression of love.
I knew from the moment I met you,
you were the one.
Lea.
-Yes?
-I do love you.
[Lea and Julia speaking Latin]
Artemus…
[Landor] Enough!
[Lea whimpers]
[dramatic music playing]
-Get out!
-You'll hang for this!
-[Artemus] You've no business here!
-Lea, finish!
Mrs. Marquis, do you
wish to see your children hang?
-Don't listen. He's bluffing!
-Continue.
-Lea!
-That's Fry's heart, no?
-Landor.
-[Julia] Lea, continue!
Ballinger, he'd do anything for you,
even murder a man.
And, Artemus, you killed him.
Please, just leave us alone.
It's almost done.
-Lea, finish!
-Lea, it is done!
It was you.
It was you who lured Fry out with a note--
It wasn't her idea! It was mine!
-I did it!
-No! Artemus!
-[Julia] No!
-[Landor grunts]
[Lea screaming] Stop!
[both grunting]
[Lea] Stop!
[Julia] Lea!
[speaking Latin]
[grunting continues]
-[shouting in Latin]
-[wood creaking]
[Lea grunts]
Lea!
-[Julia] Lea! Lea!
-Lea!
[fire roaring]
[Julia] Artemus. Artemus, help her.
Help her!
[groaning and coughing]
[Artemus] Mother, stay back!
[Julia] Artemus.
Lea. Lea! Lea!
-Artemus! Artemus!
-[coughing]
-I can't leave her!
-No!
Artemus, no. Artemus!
Artemus! No!
[Julia shrieks]
-[Landor grunts]
-[Julia] Let me go! No!
No, Artemus!
[wood creaking]
[Julia wailing]
Artemus! No!
[Poe] Lea! Lea!
[Julia] No!
[wailing] No!
[Landor] Move!
[music fades]
[bell tolling in distance]
[footsteps approaching]
I'm told he's lost no more blood
than a physician would have drawn
in the course of a normal bleeding.
Might have been the best thing for him.
More to life than meets the eye,
Landor, I admit.
I couldn't agree more.
So what now of Mrs. Marquis?
Grieving as only a mother can.
The magistrate felt she'd suffered enough.
But you'll be pleased to know
our good doctor
has submitted his resignation.
None of this pleases me, I can assure you.
Landor.
You and I could not be more dissimilar
in manner, philosophy.
But I wish to convey
that if this business
has ever rendered me…
Which is to say, if ever out
of impertinence, I have impugned…
your competence…
then I'm sorry.
Thank you, captain.
How could I have dined and fraternized
with the man all of these years?
Known his family almost as well as my own
and never fathomed
the depths of their distress.
By design, colonel.
Yes.
Yes, I suppose shame on me.
I can only assume
Artemus murdered Mr. Ballinger
to prevent him
from alerting the authorities,
and Mr. Stoddard ran
rather than become the next victim.
[Landor] You can assume that, yes.
Well, Landor,
I declare your contractual duties
fulfilled to the letter.
I hereby release you from your contract.
I hope that won't displease you.
At the very least, I hope
you won't object to accepting our thanks.
The jackals in Washington
will soon be in retreat, I hope.
I believe we have won a stay of execution.
No. Colonel.
[pensive music playing]
Don't you look fully recovered.
I know about your daughter.
[sighs] Very well.
What does Mattie have to do with anything?
Everything.
As you know full well.
It came to me while I slept.
[somber music playing]
[gasps]
The note… found in Leroy Fry's hand.
The note left for him
luring the poor bloke from his barracks.
You were careless enough
to leave that with me.
This is the other note you left.
Remember?
I'm most
struck by the shape of your characters.
Uppercase, as you well know,
are every bit as damning as lowercase.
The A, the R, the G and the E,
virtually identical to the ones
found in Leroy Fry's note.
You can imagine my astonishment.
Could the same man
have written both notes?
And why would Landor have
any reason to correspond with Leroy Fry?
As luck would have it,
I ran into la divine Patsy.
His daughter Mattie…
[Poe] She told me the whole story.
Returning home from the Academy Ball…
-[man 1] Grab her!
-[Mathilde screaming]
-[man 2] Hold her.
-No!
[Poe] …your Mattie was raped…
[Mathilde] No!
…and left for dead
by three nameless ruffians.
[man 1] Quiet.
-Please, no! No!
-[man 1] Julius, grab her legs!
-No! No, no, no!
-Grab her!
-Legs! Legs! Hold her down!
-No!
-Keep her still.
-Please!
[Poe] A bad bunch, indeed.
[Landor] Mattie.
[Poe] Just as Leroy Fry had said.
Mattie?
Oh, God! Mattie.
-Oh, my God! Come here.
-[crying]
Mattie. [crying]
[Mathilde] I'm sorry.
[sobbing]
-I'm sorry.
-It's okay.
Everything will be all right.
It'll all turn out.
[somber music playing]
[Mathilde whispering indistinctly]
Mattie, he cannot help you.
-Please, my love. Let me help you.
-[sniffles]
[panting]
[Poe] But she didn't run away, did she?
[Landor] Mattie?
Mattie.
Mattie, please. Come here.
Please, my love. Come here.
Please come here.
Don't.
Everything will be all right.
[voice breaking] Please, Mattie.
Come back.
It'll all turn out.
Don't.
I love you.
[music swells]
[music fades]
Why did you never tell me?
It's not a story
I enjoy telling.
But I would have comforted you.
Helped you as you helped me.
[sniffles]
I don't think I can
be comforted on that particular subject.
So what did I do next?
Exactly what you would have done.
Examined all assumptions, beginning with
what were the chances that two parties
would have had designs
on the same cadet in the same evening?
Small!
Small indeed!
Unless we see one party
as being contingent upon the other,
or what if one party say, Artemus and Lea,
what if they were simply
on the lookout for a dead body.
And then the opportunity
magically appears,
and they don't care who the body is,
provided it had a heart.
The one thing
they won't do for it is kill.
No, it is the other party
who is ready and willing to kill.
And to kill this man in particular.
Why? Why?
Might it be revenge, Landor?
[distant animal calls]
Patsy? Patsy?
-[Landor grunts]
-[Fry struggling]
[screaming]
[Landor grunts]
-[Fry] Help!
-Who was with you?
[struggling, choking]
[choking stops]
[rustling]
[Huntoon] Someone there?
Hello?
[shudders]
[Poe] So… the second party is interrupted,
though not before
his successful resolution.
Steals back to his cottage
in Buttermilk Falls,
where he has escaped unnoticed.
But he's shocked at being summoned back
to West Point the very next day
to learn that in the intervening hours,
the dead man's body
has been most horribly mutilated.
Thus providing his crimes
with an extraordinary cover.
Hmm.
He must think God himself was on his side.
Being engaged to solve
the very crimes that he himself committed.
And as a result, Artemus and Lea
will forever go down as murderers.
Ah… There's no forever about it.
They will be forgotten
just like the rest of us.
I shall not forget them!
Especially my Lea.
She was to be a wife, Landor, a mother.
Nor shall I forget how you
played the rest of us as fools.
Fools.
But I was your prize fool.
-Was I not?
-No.
You were the one who I was
to deliver myself to all along.
I knew that from the moment
I first met you, and here we are.
[Landor sniffles]
I, uh…
[sighs]
If you want me to say I'm sorry, I will.
I don't want your apologies.
No. I want answers.
How did you know
it was Fry who raped Mattie?
The sheep and the cows, your doing?
-Of course.
-And Ballinger?
Mmm-hmm.
[sighs deeply] Ballinger.
I had to cut his heart out.
Had to make it look
like the work of satanists.
That is no easy job for an old man.
How did you learn
of Ballinger's involvement?
Fry's diary.
Did Ballinger confess as well?
-Oh, yes, under duress.
-[Ballinger] No, please!
-[thunder rumbling]
-[Ballinger grunts]
Who else was with you?!
Julius Stoddard.
Julius.
Sorry.
[Ballinger grunting, coughing]
They both…
They both recalled her name,
and I made certain
that he recalled what she was wearing.
Every detail of her dress.
Only Stoddard, it seems,
has escaped your justice.
I haven't… the strength
or the will to chase him down.
I only hope…
that he spends the rest of his…
miserable life looking over his shoulder.
What they did
was an appalling, savage thing.
But you might have gone straight
to Thayer, secured a confession.
I didn't want them to confess.
I wanted them to die.
And so what now?
What now?
That depends on you.
I have a pair of notes…
that will send you to the gallows.
Very well.
[Poe sighs softly]
You know, Edgar, I often wish
that my Mattie had run into you
that night… of the ball.
Who knows?
We might have become a family indeed.
[inhales sharply]
I sure treasure…
[breathes shakily]
…what… What we, um…
Goodbye, Landor.
[dramatic music playing]
Rest, my love.
[melancholy music playing]
‎“分隔生命與死亡的界限
‎既朦朧又模糊
‎誰說得清生命在哪結束
‎死亡又從何開始？”-愛倫•坡
‎片名：淡藍之眸
‎先生早
‎-你是奧古斯特蘭道？
‎-是的
‎你呢？
‎希區考克上尉聽候差遣
‎我是軍校的副指揮官
‎來此告知你
‎塞耶校長有急事找你
‎-什麼樣的急事？
‎-上校會親自說明
‎-什麼時候要我過去？
‎-儘快
‎要是我婉拒呢？
‎那是你的自由，你是普通公民
‎好吧，反正今天很適合騎馬
‎（1830年，紐約州哈德遜河谷）
‎州長說你在紐約市警界是傳奇人物
‎他推薦你時，提及你的豐功偉業
‎其中包括逮捕破日幫的頭目
‎拆散惡名昭彰的衫尾幫
‎還有破解一宗駭人聽聞
‎發生於至福園的妓女命案
‎（美國西點軍校）
‎你擅長解密、鎮壓暴動
‎以及非暴力審問
‎你來自格洛斯特，父親是牧師
‎你青少年時期就來到紐約
‎而且你是名鰥夫，蘭道先生
‎喪妻三年了
‎-要來杯咖啡嗎？
‎-啤酒就行了
‎你…
‎你把這些筆記
‎放在某個櫃子裡，對吧？
‎上面還寫些什麼？
‎有沒有寫說我已多年
‎沒有上教堂了？
‎有沒有提到小女之前離家出走了？
‎我們清楚令嬡失蹤一事
‎對此深表同情
‎恕我直言，我無意冒犯
‎不會
‎不好意思，該道歉的是我
‎很抱歉，請繼續
‎蘭道先生，我們必須極度低調行事
‎我們想找一個人
‎一個資深老練的普通公民
‎能代表軍校收集情報
‎事關敏感議題，非常複雜
‎且牽扯到我們的一名學員
‎來自肯塔基州的二年級生，名叫弗萊
‎-李洛弗萊
‎-沒必要兜圈子了
‎弗萊昨晚上吊自殺
‎我深感遺憾
‎此事非常不幸
‎但你必須明白我們的立場
‎大家將這些年輕人的未來
‎寄託在我們手上
‎期望我們把他們教導成紳士和士兵
‎因此我們必須鞭策他們
‎但我們應該懂得適可而止
‎一名男孩上吊自盡
‎-這應該要找驗屍官
‎-事情恐怕沒那麼簡單
‎弗萊學員的屍體昨晚在醫院遭侵犯
‎侵犯？遭誰侵犯？
‎要是我們知道的話，就不必請你來了
‎相信貴校也有不少惡作劇之徒
‎蘭道先生，此非單純的惡作劇
‎李洛弗萊的心臟被挖了出來
‎馬奎斯醫生，對方用了什麼工具？
‎解剖刀，或任何尖銳的刀都行
‎但要把心臟挖出來可不容易
‎他的肺部和肝臟被深深劃開
‎是因為刀子要以特定角度切入
‎才得以保存心臟
‎那要怎麼保存心臟？
‎用某種容器盛裝吧
‎也許是用棉布或報紙包覆
‎再拿去冰鎮
‎哪種人辦得到這種事？
‎力氣大的人
‎所以不會是女人了？
‎我從未有榮幸見過這樣的女人
‎那醫學背景呢？
‎他必須是像你一樣
‎受過多年教育與訓練的專業人士嗎？
‎未必
‎他需要充足的光線
‎也必須知道在哪裡下刀
‎但不需要是醫生或外科醫生
‎-他肯定是…
‎-瘋子
‎逍遙法外的瘋子
‎端槍
‎蘭道先生，請見諒
‎我們現在處境艱難
‎華府某些有權勢的參議員
‎巴不得我們出紕漏，好關閉軍校
‎懇請你挽救美國軍校的榮譽
‎我會竭盡所能
‎杭圖先生，你昨晚負責看守
‎是的
‎9點30分值班，午夜便返回衛兵室
‎衛兵室在哪裡？
‎四號，柯林頓堡旁
‎我承認我不熟悉校地
‎但我們腳下這塊地
‎似乎不在柯林頓堡到北營的路上
‎-沒錯
‎-你為何繞路？
‎我在途中耳聞動靜
‎我猜是動物的叫聲
‎聽起來像奄奄一息
‎或被困在陷阱中，於是我就跑來救援
‎我很喜歡動物
‎我往這裡的方向跑
‎途中與弗萊擦身而過
‎-他看起來如何？
‎-有恙
‎他上吊的姿勢不對勁
‎看起來彷彿坐在椅子上
‎我不明白
‎他的腳當時是著地的
‎-他的腳著地？
‎-是的
‎好，那你接下來做了什麼？
‎跑走，馬上跑回北營
‎再問你最後一個問題
‎你還有看見其他人嗎？
‎沒有
‎杭圖先生
‎脖子…
‎這是第一個疑點
‎看到沒？
‎有多條勒痕，繩子勒緊他的脖子
‎但是不斷上下移動，尋找施力點
‎彷彿…
‎彷彿他當時在…掙扎
‎再來看看他的手指
‎因抓繩子而起水泡
‎努力想掙脫繩子
‎請問這是怎麼回事？
‎這很不尋常
‎若你不介意的話
‎可否摸一摸弗萊先生的後腦勺？
‎你有檢驗弗萊先生的屍體嗎？
‎當然有，那是我的工作
‎我們不是已經討論過了嗎？
‎這裡有某種挫傷
‎在頂骨的區域
‎約八公分長
‎一定是我遺漏掉了
‎弗萊先生是遭謀殺的
‎蘭道先生，這是你的意思嗎？
‎希區考克上尉，很有可能
‎醫生，誰都可能遺漏掉這個
‎蘭道先生
‎既然你同意加入調查
‎我想我們應該制定一些基本規範
‎你必須每天向我呈報
‎我再向上校呈報
‎而且不得向校內
‎或校外任何人提及此事
‎-就這樣嗎？
‎-還有最後一個條件
‎你在調查過程中必須滴酒不沾
‎大家都知道你有酗酒的問題
‎不好意思
‎-你是奧古斯特蘭道嗎？
‎-是的
‎若我沒誤會的話，你負責調查
‎李洛弗萊的死亡案件
‎沒錯，有何貴幹？
‎為了這間學校的榮譽，我有義務分享
‎我所得到的一些結論
‎結論？
‎針對弗萊死亡一事
‎我洗耳恭聽
‎你要找的人
‎是一名詩人
‎考科藍二等兵
‎李洛弗萊的屍體被帶回醫院時
‎是由你負責看守？
‎是的，警探
‎-看守期間有何異樣？
‎-一直到2點30分才有
‎-我被卸除職務
‎-誰下的令？
‎-二等兵，是誰下的令？
‎-我也不知道
‎我只知道是一名軍官
‎-他沒有透露自己的身分？
‎-沒有，警探
‎但軍官沒必要對我多作解釋
‎這名軍官對你說了什麼？
‎他說：“二等兵，謝謝，你可以走了
‎我要卸除你的職務”
‎-你不感到不尋常嗎？
‎-是的，很不尋常
‎-你有看到這名軍官的臉嗎？
‎-沒有
‎我手上只有一根蠟燭，當時天色很暗
‎好吧，那你怎麼知道對方是軍官？
‎因為他肩上的橫槓
‎但我必須承認，那非常古怪
‎-怎麼說？
‎-那些橫槓
‎他左肩上的橫槓不見了
‎歡迎你大駕光臨
‎一看就知道你需要來一杯
‎光看到酒就全身暖和起來了
‎-班尼
‎-是
‎-敬…規範
‎-管他的規範
‎派希
‎怎麼愁眉苦臉的？
‎你聽說那可憐的學員的事了嗎？
‎-他們說他過了好幾小時後才死
‎-“他們”？
‎他
‎你不是該去參加獨奏會嗎？
‎晚安，獨奏會？
‎不，沒有人在乎我去不去
‎我在軍校裡沒沒無聞
‎況且，我在這種地方學到的東西
‎比教室學到的還多
‎我相信你
‎請坐，請坐下來，請就…
‎-座
‎-對，謝謝
‎我是四年級生，叫愛倫坡
‎埃德加愛倫坡
‎看來你口很渴
‎借酒消愁嘛
‎你是怎麼知道李洛弗萊的事的？
‎當然是從杭圖口中得知的
‎他像個傳報員一樣，不斷散播消息
‎也許不久會有人吊死他
‎你是否暗指有人吊死弗萊先生？
‎我沒有暗指任何事情
‎你為何認為
‎把李洛弗萊的心臟挖出來的人
‎是一名詩人？
‎這個嘛…
‎心臟若非象徵，就什麼也不是
‎去除象徵意義的話，還剩下什麼？
‎僅剩下一團肌肉
‎長得跟膀胱沒什麼兩樣
‎移除一個人的心臟是一大罪行
‎而除了詩人以外，還有誰更有能力
‎做這件事？
‎這名詩人也太沒有想像力了吧…
‎你無法否認這項殘暴之舉
‎會驚動你心深處的文學迴響
‎套用約翰蘇克林那首迷人的歌曲
‎“既然得不到你的心
‎那就把我的心還來”
‎甚至是《聖經》
‎“上帝啊，請為我造一顆純潔的心”
‎“憂傷痛悔的心，你必不輕看”
‎那凶手很可能是個信教的瘋子
‎不，聽好了，我忘了告訴你
‎我也是一名詩人
‎因此也擁有詩人的思維
‎我不常讀詩
‎何必呢？你是美國人
‎那你呢？
‎我是藝術家，不屬於任何國家
‎笑什麼，蘭道先生？
‎感謝你的幫忙
‎去調查一名叫拉夫堡的學員
‎他曾是李洛弗萊的室友
‎但他們之間鬧得不愉快
‎起因不明
‎拉夫堡先生
‎請向蘭道先生說明
‎你是如何認識弗萊先生的
‎好的，我們原本是室友
‎有鬧得不愉快嗎？
‎也不是鬧得不愉快，只是…
‎我們決定各走各的路
‎基於什麼原因？
‎也沒什麼，就…
‎自然而然地如此
‎若你知道任何有關弗萊先生的事
‎必須據實以告
‎是這樣的
‎我會說他結交了一群
‎壞朋友
‎至少他是這麼形容的
‎那告訴我，“壞朋友”
‎指的是其他的學員嗎？
‎他沒多說，但我是這麼猜想的
‎你為何不早點告訴我們？
‎我沒想到兩者會有所關聯
‎畢竟這是很久以前的事了
‎你可以走了
‎斯達德先生
‎你是弗萊生前最後一個看到他的人
‎是的，長官
‎-說話大聲點
‎-我有點不舒服
‎我確實在案發當晚深夜看見李洛
‎在回營房的路上與他擦肩而過
‎你跟他說過話嗎？
‎他把我攔下來，問我附近有沒有軍官
‎弗萊先生神態如何？
‎當時很暗，我記不清楚
‎你有沒有看到他身上拿著一條繩子？
‎就我所知沒有
‎倒是有一件事
‎弗萊離開前，我問他這麼晚要去哪
‎然後呢？
‎他說：“處理要事”
‎你認為那是什麼意思？
‎不知道
‎你可以走了
‎-上尉，打擾了
‎-什麼事？
‎老天
‎“冷泉有一頭牛和一隻羊遭殘殺肢解
‎其胸腔遭殘忍地切開，心臟被挖出”
‎難道這人不放過任何一個生靈嗎？
‎我們無法確定這出自同一個人之手
‎什麼？
‎這只是巧合嗎？
‎明早6點開始
‎所有人員只能去上課
‎吃飯及參加禱告會
‎其餘活動一律禁止
‎若你的同學問起
‎我們僅談到你和李洛弗萊的關係
‎我跟他毫無關係，我不認識他
‎-什麼？
‎-我不認識那個人
‎-看來我誤會你了
‎-你也不是第一個誤會我的人
‎若你不是來找我討論案情
‎那你找我做什麼？
‎我要雇用你
‎不過沒有酬勞
‎也不能讓你的同學知道你在做什麼
‎直到你早已完成任務
‎要是他們發現了
‎也很有可能會辱罵你
‎真是個令人無法抗拒的條件
‎不，請繼續說
‎好極了，我要請你破解
‎一小段不完整的字條
‎你必須暗中行事，也必須非常精準
‎好消息，我破解了你給我的訊息
‎是手寫的，攸關私事
‎事發當晚，弗萊將其帶在身上
‎我們可從中推斷
‎這張字條足以在案發當晚
‎將他引出營房
‎因其餘的訊息從他的手中被撕走
‎我們可以推斷
‎這張字條能揭露作者身分
‎對方以粗糙的方式寫出黑色大寫字母
‎也顯示作者想刻意隱藏身分
‎這是某種邀約
‎或者更準確來說是圈套
‎圈套？
‎清楚了這點之後…可以借我嗎？
‎我們把注意力集中在第三行
‎因為那是完整的字
‎“Be”，但後面接的是什麼？
‎某個L開頭的字
‎“小”？“幸運”？
‎不對，這都跟邀約無關
‎“處於迷失”？不對，這文法太鬆散了
‎若對方希望李洛弗萊
‎在特定的時間地點出現
‎那就只有一個可能，“遲到”
‎“遲到”
‎看一看第三行
‎第一個字就太好猜了
‎答案就是“別”
‎所以是“別遲到”
‎蘭道先生，仔細看
‎我們快要找出合適的人選了
‎若弗萊要前往一個既定地點
‎那從作者的觀點來說，他要過來了
‎所以是“來吧，弗萊先生”
‎破解完這一句之後，想都不用想
‎就知道下一個字一定會是“快點”
‎拼湊起來就大功告成
‎“別遲到，快點來”
‎完成了，我要把這個小小謎團的解答
‎交給你
‎了不起，謝謝你
‎-我只有一個問題
‎-嗯？
‎前兩行破解出來了嗎？
‎我不得不知難而退
‎你很會拼字嗎？
‎我拼字能力一流
‎而且我還有權威作證
‎斯托克紐因頓的約翰布蘭斯比牧師
‎那我猜你從來沒有犯過常人的錯誤
‎把同音字的拼法搞混
‎比方說，“他們是”、“他們的”
‎還有“那裡”
‎常見的謬誤
‎這的確是邀約，“在那裡和我碰面”
‎當然我們還不知道碰面地點，對吧？
‎但我們知道結尾是字母N和G
‎碼頭！
‎-而且是碼頭旁的海灣
‎-猜得好
‎所以是“我會在碼頭旁的海灣”
‎“在晚上11點到那裡和我碰面”
‎所以比較可能是“不要遲到，來見我”
‎你覺得這是什麼線索嗎？
‎他明明可以在任何地方和學員碰面
‎何必大費周章跑去碼頭？
‎因為對方不是學員，而是個女人
‎蘭道先生，你一直都知道答案
‎那只是我的推論
‎若我們要找的真的是名女人
‎那我相信我已經看過她了
‎李洛弗萊遇害隔日早晨
‎在我得知消息前
‎我一醒來，即開始朗誦
‎一首詩的開場白
‎這段開場白講述的是
‎一名悲痛無比的神祕女子
‎接著，食堂外面出現了一位
‎我生平見過最美麗的女人
‎她是誰？
‎我毫無頭緒
‎但你為何相信這首詩或那名女子
‎和弗萊先生有關？
‎不為人知的暴行
‎無可告人的威迫
‎一名陌生女子
‎你在任何一個早上
‎都有可能寫出這首詩
‎但那不是我寫的，是別人叫我寫的
‎別人叫你寫的？
‎誰叫你寫的？
‎我母親
‎她已不在人間
‎死了將近20年
‎跟我說說坡這個人怎麼樣
‎小坡啊
‎很可愛的一個男孩
‎彬彬有禮、口若懸河
‎沒錯，而且他這個人很不尋常
‎因為他話很多？
‎不是，因為他只會做一些
‎毫無邏輯的幻想
‎他宣稱有一首詩
‎和李洛弗萊之死有關
‎還宣稱那首詩
‎是他亡母在他睡夢中叫他寫的
‎在所有人之中，你應該最清楚
‎那些逝去的亡魂
‎永遠與我們同在
‎人為了逃過死劫，什麼事都做得出來
‎用某種容器盛裝吧
‎也許是用棉布或報紙包覆
‎再拿去冰鎮
‎（到冰窖碰面，鼓起勇氣）
‎很好，你收到我的字條了
‎-有人跟蹤你嗎？
‎-跟蹤？
‎太不專業了，當然沒有
‎-這是什麼？
‎-犯案現場
‎第二次犯案
‎弗萊的心臟被帶來這裡
‎你提到弗萊的心臟被挖出
‎讓你聯想到《聖經》
‎不得不承認，我早就往那方向推斷了
‎只不過不是《聖經》
‎而是宗教
‎這確實看起來像某種儀式
‎血和蠟燭以特定方式擺設
‎-圓圈
‎-還有三角形
‎弗萊的心臟很可能被放在裡面
‎我有個老朋友可能幫得上忙
‎尚恩佩裴教授專攻符號…
‎-佩裴
‎-…儀式和神祕學
‎-教授
‎-佩裴可說是
‎-我這輩子見過…
‎-請進，我在後面這裡
‎-抱歉打擾
‎-…最古怪的人
‎我帶來一個奇特的東西，想給你看看
‎這一定是魔法陣
‎我記得曾在《紅龍》中看過
‎若沒記錯，魔法師會站在
‎三角形裡面
‎獨自一人？
‎他可能有一些助手
‎兩邊放滿蠟燭、火把，到處都有光
‎堪稱一場光之饗宴
‎古斯，到第三個書櫃
‎從上面數來第二層櫃子
‎最上面的那本書
‎就是那本
‎皮埃爾德朗克，可怕的獵巫者
‎-坡先生，你會讀法文嗎？
‎-會
‎安靜地讀吧，在中間那一頁
‎德朗克將600名巴斯克女巫處死
‎並留下你手中的那本巨作
‎但我想給你的書是
‎亨利勒克的《魔鬼話語》
‎他在寫完之前處決了700名女巫
‎但書據說已遭摧毀
‎傳聞遭摧毀的那本書
‎還有兩三份一模一樣的版本
‎對許多神祕學家來說
‎那本書可是求之不得
‎-為什麼？
‎勒克在書中留下了…
‎長生不死的祕方
‎天啊
‎“惡天使之中常言
‎女巫在安息日的饗宴上
‎僅能準備以下食材
‎基督教徒絕不吃的污穢動物
‎未受洗過的孩童心臟
‎以及上吊者的心臟”
‎我需要你悄悄滲入軍校
‎看誰跟神祕學有關聯
‎有話快說
‎近日有人對我作出一項提議
‎相當黑暗且有違基督教的提議
‎-有違基督教？
‎-是
‎我因此質疑自己的信仰
‎開始鑽研古老神祕學
‎-神祕學？
‎-他是指黑魔法，是誰？
‎-告訴我們
‎-我發誓不透露他的名字
‎到底是誰？
‎怎麼問我都不會回答
‎就算上帝親自威嚇我
‎我也會守口如瓶
‎-你可以和我們一同禱告
‎-不，我答應對方了
‎-當有人要你質疑信仰…
‎-我不能張揚
‎是馬奎斯嗎？
‎漢彌頓，別亂說話
‎這下有名字了，但必須找到對應的臉
‎眩暈？
‎我整個頭暈目眩
‎你的心跳很快
‎好吧，坡先生，今天待在室內
‎好好照顧自己
‎把這個拿給洛克中尉及他的班長
‎亞提莫斯，我兒子
‎他會幫你卸除你今日的職務
‎你今天無法上課，因為你感到
‎眩暈？
‎我還有一個更嚴重的病痛
‎一股強大的厭倦感
‎“強大的厭倦感”？
‎令我極度不適
‎坡，小心點
‎你可以自己去問醫生
‎中尉，是真的
‎家父的確跟我說
‎他從未見過如此嚴重的症狀
‎好吧
‎但我要因你的厚顏無恥懲罰你
‎扣三分
‎立刻返回營房
‎軍官巡房時，你最好沒跑掉
‎-你叫坡嗎？
‎-是的
‎亞提莫斯馬奎斯
‎不得不說
‎你如此明目張膽真令人佩服
‎今晚11點在北營18號碰面
‎抱歉晚到，希望沒讓你等太久
‎這裡真棒
‎好多書！
‎你完全提起了我的興趣
‎該從哪裡開始呢？
‎差強人意的菲尼莫爾庫柏
‎不過這也算是必收藏的經典吧
‎真是坐擁書城
‎《埃及史》，琳瑯滿目
‎我識破你了
‎你讓我以為你不讀詩
‎我確實不讀詩
‎拜倫
‎-這是我個人的最愛，蘭道先生…
‎-麻煩你
‎…而且書都被翻爛了
‎那是我女兒的
‎令嬡已不在？
‎對，她跟別人跑了
‎你認識對方嗎？
‎不熟
‎而她不會再回來了？
‎不大可能
‎那我們在這世界上都孤身一人
‎但你還有你母親
‎她仍會跟你說話
‎-儘管她死了
‎-是啊
‎是的，她不時會和我說話
‎順便一提，我所有的優點都是來自她
‎令嬡，冒昧請問，她叫什麼名字？
‎瑪蒂達
‎小瑪
‎蘭道先生，你不必多說了
‎-你說你有所發現
‎-不，不僅如此
‎一名叫馬奎斯的人
‎那位醫生
‎不，他的兒子，亞提莫斯
‎而我成功進入了他難以滲透的小團體
‎我又帶來了一個上帝的造物
‎這是美妙的派希送的
‎坡，你會通報我們違反宵禁嗎？
‎我們稍微打破戒律會冒犯到你嗎？
‎貝林傑先生，我不僅沒有被冒犯到
‎我還要…
‎再來一輪
‎喝下去
‎小妞，全喝光
‎貝林傑，你今晚真是盛氣凌人
‎麻煩你，再來一杯
‎感激不盡
‎我可以喝一整晚
‎貝林傑，慢著點
‎那可是我費盡千辛萬苦才弄到的
‎坡
‎聽說你是出版過作品的詩人
‎人們說我天賦異稟
‎那就來一場誦詩會
‎給我們一點消遣
‎我在百慕達遇見一名光溜溜的浪女
‎她自以為聰明
‎卻略遜我一籌
‎她認為一絲不掛地被追求，太過淫穢
‎於是我追上、壓上並搞上她
‎-坡，真絕妙
‎-厲害
‎了不起
‎輸家是七
‎贏家是J
‎坡，你今天真幸運
‎謝謝
‎坡，蘭道警探是否真的訊問過你
‎關於弗萊的事？
‎他誤以為我和弗萊是至交
‎你們是嗎？
‎不是
‎不出所料
‎弗萊唯一能引人注意的方法
‎就是上吊自殺
‎他應該是因為求愛不成而自殺的
‎斯達德，他跟誰求愛？
‎亞提莫斯，那你妹妹呢？
‎她是不是讓弗萊一見傾心？
‎拜託，藍迪
‎這裡就你和弗萊最親近
‎最親近他的人
‎是你才對吧
‎好了，剛才玩到哪？
‎坡
‎坡先生，你不必遵守宵禁嗎？
‎給我解釋清楚
‎你三小時前就該熄燈了
‎對不起，長官
‎你每次道歉都只是空口說白話
‎別忘了李洛弗萊是在宵禁過後喪命的
‎立刻返回營房
‎你還活著就該慶幸了
‎謝謝，長官
‎動作快
‎小瑪？
‎“主啊，以祢的恩惠和慈愛待我
‎因為在死地無人紀念祢
‎在陰間有誰稱謝祢？
‎主啊，因祢的恩惠
‎以祢的恩惠和慈愛待我
‎我因憂愁眼睛乾癟”
‎你是蘭道先生，不是嗎？
‎是的
‎我是李洛的母親
‎請你收下這個
‎李洛的日記
‎他記錄了過去三年的生活點滴
‎我不記得…
‎很抱歉
‎請節哀
‎我不記得他的私物中有日記
‎是貝林傑先生寄給我的
‎-貝林傑先生？
‎-是的
‎他一得知死訊
‎就馬上跑去李洛的營房幫忙
‎那體貼的孩子把日記寄給我
‎原來如此
‎而且方才，他一看見我
‎就說：“妳應該帶李洛的日記
‎回肯塔基
‎想把它燒掉的話，儘管去做吧”
‎真貼心
‎但我都看不懂
‎上面寫滿了數字和字母
‎不過…看到軍方讓你帶領調查
‎我覺得這應該交給你才對
‎我會時常回來見你
‎-幫忙照料她…
‎-我明白
‎…我們同舟共濟
‎醫生
‎蘭道先生，遇到你真巧
‎容我介紹內人茱莉亞
‎久仰大名
‎幸會
‎你不是調查弗萊先生之死的人嗎？
‎是的
‎我們才剛聊到這件事
‎我先生說即使他的英勇嘗試
‎弗萊先生的遺體狀態不佳
‎無法瞻仰遺容
‎他的父母真可憐
‎的確
‎這整件事令我們震驚不已
‎放心，我一定會逮到凶手的
‎很高興認識妳
‎親愛的
‎蘭道先生，聽說你是鰥夫
‎沒錯
‎我深表同情
‎夫人蒙主恩召是最近的事嗎？
‎已過了兩年
‎才搬來高地幾個月後就過世了
‎突然病逝嗎？
‎並非突然
‎可惜拖太久了
‎我與你一同哀悼
‎-請節哀
‎-謝謝
‎太棒了
‎埃德加，就說我妹妹是才女吧？
‎親愛的，太棒了，我感動到落淚
‎是啊
‎馬奎斯小姐，彈得真好
‎-千真萬確
‎-是的
‎妳註定會萬古不朽
‎藍迪，不會有女人想要長生不死的
‎我頓時想起托馬斯格雷的一首詩
‎“花開無人賞”
‎“芳香也成荒”
‎這是我最愛的一首詩
‎那妳覺得我的小門徒如何？
‎我認為坡先生當門徒是大材小用
‎他跟你們在一起，卻出淤泥而不染
‎好了，麗雅
‎夠了，吃晚飯前休息一下
‎-各位，失陪了
‎-謝謝，麗雅
‎藍迪，椅子拿來
‎斯達德，快點，準備棋盤
‎好，我好無聊
‎那又怎樣
‎她生病了
‎不該讓她抱病宴客…
‎馬奎斯小姐
‎不好意思
‎這將是莫大榮幸
‎若我能邀妳週六與我一同出去
‎我相信你，坡先生
‎但我恐怕週六有約了
‎這樣啊
‎所以你想要週六碰面？
‎週日也行，只要合妳的意
‎週一也無妨
‎你想在哪裡碰面？
‎讓我猜，吉斯角？情人步道？
‎不是
‎都不是
‎我在想墓園
‎墓園？
‎真有意思
‎是的，我也這麼認為
‎那麼，晚安
‎真是一片荒涼
‎要欣賞高地的美景
‎葉落之時是最佳時機
‎為何？
‎草木沒有錦上添花的作用
‎反而只會阻礙上帝原來的設計
‎真浪漫
‎你真是滿嘴不離上帝和死亡
‎死亡的確是詩人最鍾愛的主題
‎請坐
‎-真宜人
‎-的確，我最喜歡的地方
‎陰沉很適合你
‎比你穿的制服還要搭
‎全世界只有亞提莫斯跟你有得比
‎我從未見過他憂鬱的一面
‎他幾乎都活在自己的世界裡
‎長期沉浸在痛苦之中
‎並非不可能
‎但無法永遠持續下去
‎你們倆有許多共同點
‎希望妳不會冷
‎顯然寒冬已降臨
‎拜託別說了
‎我不是來這裡聊天氣的，真無趣
‎抱歉，我只是擔心妳會著涼
‎那請繼續吧
‎對我宣揚你至死不渝的愛
‎我們就可以好好回家了
‎-我只是在說…
‎-對不起
‎抱歉，我真無禮，不曉得為什麼
‎妳確實冷了
‎馬奎斯小姐，要不要穿我的斗篷？
‎-不必了
‎-真的沒關係…
‎我…
‎-什麼？
‎-馬奎斯小姐
‎麗雅
‎麗雅…怎麼回事？
‎天啊，麗雅
‎妳還好嗎？
‎-麗雅
‎-我很好
‎妳確定妳沒事嗎？我嚇壞了
‎這很常發生，不必擔心
‎妳的…
‎我與妳意氣相投，所以我想和妳分享
‎我母親仍存在我的生命中
‎在夢中和清醒時皆然
‎是的
‎有時候，我認為亡者糾纏我們
‎是因為我們愛他們愛得不夠深
‎我們遺忘了他們
‎雖然不是故意的，但還是遺忘了
‎他們是因為被遺棄了才會糾纏不放
‎還是別想太多好了
‎我想讓你知道，我很感謝你
‎當我張開眼睛看見你
‎我注視著你的雙眼
‎發現了前所未有的東西
‎千年難得一見
‎謝謝
‎住手
‎混帳，給我安分點
‎離麗雅遠一點
‎住手
‎貝林傑，住手
‎否則給我準備上法庭
‎醜八怪
‎你沒事吧？
‎那野人顯然知道麗雅比較喜歡我
‎-若他想把我嚇跑…
‎-嚇跑？
‎-他一副要殺了你的樣子
‎-殺了我？
‎我才不會讓他阻撓我追求心之所向
‎我才會殺了他
‎大家老是低估我
‎朋友、同學，甚至是我的施主
‎-派希，謝謝
‎-所有人都是
‎所有人…
‎除了我的慈母
‎感謝你剛才挺身相助
‎很少有人能讓我出其不意
‎你也讓人出其不意，不是嗎？蘭道
‎無意冒犯
‎但你比外表看起來還要老成持重
‎告訴我，你是否真的曾經
‎只靠一個犀利眼神
‎就讓凶手招供？
‎只要有足夠的耐心
‎不必開口，嫌犯就會訊問自己
‎蘭道，有你的陪伴真好
‎我有一天會寫一首詩
‎讓你名留青史
‎經過這場攻擊事件
‎你仍不把藍迪貝林傑當嫌犯？
‎那這對你的調查來說
‎會有什麼影響？
‎我想把焦點放在亞提莫斯馬奎斯身上
‎看來妳認識他？
‎誰不認識？
‎多麼英俊瀟灑
‎這種人感覺註定要英年早逝
‎但他看起來不像會使用暴力的人
‎總是非常沉著冷靜
‎或許凶手不是他
‎他散發一種特質，全家人都是
‎一副犯了什麼罪的樣子
‎有哪個家庭沒有犯過罪的？
‎-上尉
‎-是貝林傑先生
‎他失蹤了
‎上尉，這裡
‎老天爺
‎貝林傑先生的傷口切緣
‎不像弗萊的乾淨俐落
‎凶手應該不是同一個人
‎至於被閹割的事…
‎這…
‎閹割？
‎天啊，蘭道
‎我們毫無進展
‎跟一個月前沒兩樣
‎有進展了
‎-遲早會水落石出的
‎-告訴我
‎你有沒有找到更多撒旦儀式的證據？
‎或是那個叫考科藍二等兵
‎拋下李洛弗萊屍體的軍官？
‎還有弗萊的日記
‎你有沒有找到任何一條可用的線索？
‎有個瘋子逍遙法外
‎把我學員的心臟挖出
‎我的學員紛紛不敢值勤
‎不敢出營房也不敢睡覺
‎敢睡覺的，也都是抱著槍入睡
‎我開始認為你不覺得我有能力
‎繼續進行調查
‎謝謝，醫生
‎我們質疑的不是你的能力
‎而是你的忠誠
‎這有沒有可能是出自坡先生之手？
‎坡？
‎他昨日還跟同學得意洋洋地分享
‎他和貝林傑先生的精彩打鬥
‎還揚言他們下次起爭執
‎他就要殺了他
‎你見過坡吧
‎你真心覺得他有辦法制伏貝林傑？
‎不，但他不必靠蠻力
‎用槍就能輕鬆解決
‎無論他和貝林傑是敵是友
‎坡和李洛弗萊並沒有任何關聯
‎-他們甚至素不相識
‎-他們彼此相識
‎去年夏天還打了一場架
‎看來他沒有告訴你吧？
‎那就逮捕他吧
‎既然你這麼篤定是他，就逮捕他吧
‎我們只有動機
‎該提供證據的人是你
‎蘭道先生，你是否對敝校懷有不滿？
‎是這個原因嗎？
‎我正在冒生命危險
‎為你們寶貴的機構展開調查
‎不過是的
‎我一向認為軍校
‎只會剝奪青年的自由意志
‎以規範和規定侷限他們
‎讓他們喪失理性判斷、失去人性
‎你是在說
‎軍校必須為這些死亡負責嗎？
‎是的，對方跟軍校有關聯
‎所以軍校本身也有問題
‎胡說八道
‎照你的邏輯來說
‎基督徒所犯下的罪行
‎都會牽連到耶穌基督
‎沒錯
‎我請你接下這份工作時
‎你說你跟李洛弗萊毫無瓜葛，所以…
‎就先從這裡開始吧，如何？
‎-這不全然是事實…
‎-哎呀
‎為什麼只要跟你有關的事
‎都要搞得這麼複雜？
‎事實在哪裡？我只要單純的事實
‎是或否
‎告訴我真相
‎你是否認識李洛弗萊？
‎是
‎你有沒有和李洛弗萊說過話？
‎有的
‎你有沒有殺死李洛弗萊？
‎你有沒有殺死藍道夫貝林傑？
‎你有沒有褻瀆他們的屍體？
‎-沒有，我拿自己的性命發誓…
‎-但你不否認
‎你曾威脅過這兩名死者？
‎我之前威脅貝林傑…
‎都只是氣話
‎-那弗萊呢？
‎-我從來沒有威脅過他，我只是…
‎坡，我觀察出相當令人不安的規律
‎惹到你的人最後都命喪黃泉
‎而且重要器官都被挖出來了
‎蘭道先生
‎我來這裡不久，但如果我要殺死
‎每一個霸凌我的學員
‎那這裡的學員軍團成員
‎恐怕只會剩下個位數
‎若你非要知道，我來這裡第一天開始
‎就是大家嘲弄的對象
‎我的行為舉止、年齡和性格…
‎以及我的外觀
‎哪怕我能活千百輩子
‎也無法治癒
‎我這一生所受過的傷
‎是的，我犯下許多過錯
‎但那可絕對沒有
‎我絕對沒有殺過人
‎你現在相信我了嗎？
‎你應該多注意自己的言行
‎我可以暫時阻止希區考克鎖定你
‎但你再欺騙我的話
‎他們把你抓去關我也不會幫你
‎明白嗎？
‎失陪了，我晚餐有約
‎感謝你與我們一同哀悼
‎藍道夫的不幸逝世
‎那孩子就像我們的家人
‎蘭道先生
‎你不覺得小犬非常英俊嗎？
‎令嬡和令郎都外貌出眾
‎是的，我們有優越的基因
‎但我不得不說，你是難得一見的人才
‎絕頂聰明
‎這是我們這裡極為少見的特質
‎蘭道先生，憑你的才智
‎我希望在你的正式工作結束之後
‎能為我解開一個謎團
‎-謎團？
‎-令人百思不解的怪事
‎週一的獨奏會
‎有人亂翻我的物品
‎那…
‎-壞人到處都是
‎-父親，當真嗎？
‎我倒是認為那傢伙只是很無禮
‎雖然我不知道對方是誰
‎但你還是得小心，亞提莫斯
‎-真的要小心
‎-母親
‎對方八成只是個無聊的老頭子
‎閒閒沒事做，毫無生活可言
‎某個住在農舍的村民
‎蘭道先生，你不覺得嗎？
‎-你不是住在農舍嗎？
‎-亞提莫斯
‎你搞不好認識我說的那種人
‎說不定你剛好有個
‎喜歡在酒館喝酒的朋友
‎夠了，拜託，我厭惡這種行為
‎我最討厭你這樣無端生事
‎-母親，我不明白妳的意思
‎-當然了
‎我平常說什麼話也沒人在乎
‎沒有人會在乎
‎-丹尼爾，你說是不是？
‎-兒子，別這樣
‎請原諒內人
‎貝林傑先生之死
‎讓我們家被哀愁籠罩
‎蘭道先生，不曉得你願不願意
‎去書房跟我談談？
‎樂意之至
‎抱歉，警官
‎天天過著如坐針氈的生活
‎讓我們難以承受
‎-不必道歉
‎-是
‎逢這時節，又不得自由活動…
‎我完全能理解
‎醫生，我注意到
‎令嬡是不是身體有恙？
‎觀察真敏銳
‎是的
‎是的，她…
‎她一路走來很辛苦
‎從小就這樣了
‎她罹患重病
‎讓她在四下無人時癲癇發作
‎大腦停止運作，身體像葫蘆一樣搖動
‎多麼美麗的孩子
‎註定要結婚生子，成為達官貴人
‎卻同時又身患重病
‎相當不幸
‎兩位，麗雅在彈琴，請你們一同欣賞
‎謝謝，兒子
‎走吧？
‎不介意的話，我想出去透透氣
‎沒問題
‎父親，一起玩個遊戲
‎跟上次一樣嗎？
‎還是換個更有挑戰性的遊戲？
‎-太出色了
‎-才不
‎還可以吧
‎妳不知曉妳彈的曲子對我有何影響
‎對大家都是，真的，我…
‎-什麼？
‎-我…
‎我不知道該如何啟齒，但我發現
‎我願為妳做任何事情
‎埃德加
‎蘭道先生，需要幫你找什麼東西嗎？
‎妳這麼快就恢復了
‎不好意思
‎我以為我偏頭痛又發作了
‎沒想到休息一下就沒事了
‎而且現在神清氣爽
‎把這老舊的東西放回去吧
‎肯定不合身
‎我和醫生一直在找它
‎結果找到了
‎親愛的，你看警官在衣櫃裡找到什麼
‎記得亞提莫斯小時候
‎在家裡都會穿在身上嗎？
‎-記得嗎？親愛的
‎-記得，母親
‎-那是我兄弟的外套
‎-你兄弟？
‎那是他唯一遺留下來的物品
‎怎麼會在你手上？
‎也許亞提莫斯能回答
‎伊森
‎什麼風把你吹來的？
‎又有學員失蹤了
‎我已組織搜救團隊
‎會在一小時內出發
‎我們要翻遍每一寸土地
‎上帝保佑，我不敢想像這次…
‎各位
‎我剛去斯達德先生的營房
‎他的行李箱是空的
‎裡面沒有任何便衣
‎我認為他逃跑了
‎逃跑了？
‎弗萊的日記顯示
‎斯達德和貝林傑
‎都和李洛弗萊是好朋友
‎他一定怕自己是下一個受害者
‎所以逃跑了
‎儘管如此，那亞提莫斯
‎怎麼會有軍官的外套？
‎若他有涉案
‎我們怎麼能不馬上逮捕他？
‎他太過冷靜沉著，一定會堅決否認
‎我想試試最後一個辦法
‎他身邊最親密的好友都死了
‎我必須立刻向總統報告
‎凶手已逮捕到案
‎蘭道，我們已逮到凶手了，不是嗎？
‎埃德加
‎教授？
‎佩裴
‎上次來此，你提到獵巫者和一本書
‎是的，《魔鬼話語》
‎亨利勒克
‎勒克是牧師嗎？
‎被燒死的牧師
‎我在睡夢中得到靈感
‎狂野疾風
‎奔馳而下
‎我悲痛地懇求她快一點
‎“麗諾”
‎她不願回答
‎無盡的夜晚籠罩著她
‎僅露出她的淡藍之眸
‎黯然之夜
‎怒火燃燒
‎僅剩下
‎那雙致命淡藍之眸
‎發現其中的關聯了嗎？
‎麗諾
‎麗雅
‎這是妳深埋在心中的痛苦
‎反映出妳一直以來的壓抑
‎這首詩
‎在對我們說話
‎還記得你說你願為我做任何事情嗎？
‎魔鬼的崇拜者
‎-謝謝，佩裴
‎-不會
‎蘭道先生
‎你們一家人
‎是一團謎
‎我一直摸不透誰是一家之主
‎我曾經懷疑過你們每一個人
‎但我萬萬沒想到
‎幕後主使會是一個亡魂
‎什麼意思？
‎亨利勒克牧師
‎獵巫者中的佼佼者
‎直到他最後也成了獵物
‎你在說什麼？
‎令嬡患有癲癇症，不是嗎？
‎她能勉強度日是因為她跟某人有接觸
‎一個在暗中指導她的人
‎就是他
‎蘭道先生，我開始懷疑你瘋了
‎你在暗示什麼？
‎勒克的《魔鬼話語》
‎與魔鬼溝通
‎不是我熟悉的嗜好，蘭道先生
‎我從未讀過他的書
‎令嬡會不會與亡者溝通？
‎她的癲癇年復一年每況愈下
‎我…
‎各種療法我都試過了
‎醫生宣告她只剩三個月可活
‎你知道那是什麼感覺嗎？
‎入睡時不知道自己女兒
‎能否熬到明日？
‎但有一天，她跟我說
‎她遇見了一個人
‎她的曾曾祖父
‎勒克？
‎亨利勒克非邪惡之人
‎他只是被誤解了
‎他們發誓弗萊已經死了
‎他們發誓他們不可能殺死任何人
‎你竟然相信他們
‎我別無選擇
‎你是醫生，科學之人
‎怎能輕信這種謬論？
‎因為…
‎因為我救不了她
‎我自己的專長辜負了我
‎我為了麗雅犧牲一切
‎怎能拒絕另一個解救她的可能？
‎醫生
‎和亡者溝通
‎非正常之舉，但殺人…
‎殘殺無辜性命
‎太沒人性了
‎有人必須為此負責
‎我讓她這麼做只因為…奇蹟似地
‎她的症狀似乎有所改善
‎醫生，你家人在哪裡？
‎你的孩子在哪？
‎坡先生剛才在這裡
‎他跟…亞提莫斯一起走了
‎他的外套怎麼還在大廳裡？
‎醫生，麗雅在哪裡？
‎醫生，你的家人在哪裡？
‎作用開始消退了
‎麗雅
‎繼續
‎這是怎麼回事？
‎再忍耐一下就結束了
‎我好不舒服
‎-我以為…
‎-不
‎再過幾分鐘，我就自由了
‎自由？
‎是的
‎拜託，麗雅，我…
‎我必須這麼做
‎你明白吧
‎犧牲是愛的終極表現
‎我第一眼看見你就知道
‎你是我的命中註定
‎麗雅
‎-什麼事？
‎-我真心愛妳
‎夠了
‎-出去！
‎-你們會被吊死的
‎你沒理由來這裡
‎麗雅，快下手
‎馬奎斯夫人
‎妳想看到自己的子女被吊死嗎？
‎-別聽他亂講
‎-繼續
‎-麗雅
‎-那是弗萊的心臟，不是嗎？
‎-蘭道
‎-麗雅，繼續
‎貝林傑，他願為妳上山下海
‎連殺人也願意
‎而亞提莫斯，你殺了他
‎請你離開，快結束了
‎-麗雅，快下手
‎-麗雅，早就結束了
‎原來是妳
‎是妳寫字條引誘弗萊去…
‎不是她的主意，是我的
‎-是我做的
‎-不，亞提莫斯
‎-不
‎-拜託，住手
‎住手
‎麗雅
‎-麗雅
‎亞提莫斯
‎母親，別過來
‎麗雅
‎亞提莫斯，不
‎放開我，不
‎亞提莫斯
‎亞提莫斯，不
‎麗雅
‎不
‎醫生說他只有輕微失血
‎傷勢不嚴重
‎這或許是最好的結果了
‎不得不承認，真是人不可貌相
‎一點也沒錯
‎我們該拿馬奎斯夫人怎麼辦？
‎就讓她這個母親好好哀悼吧
‎法官認為她已吃了不少苦
‎值得你高興的是
‎我們的醫生已遞了辭呈
‎我跟你保證，我一點都不高興
‎蘭道
‎你我的性格和理念可說是南轅北轍
‎但我想表達的是
‎若我在這整件事情中得到任何領悟
‎那就是…若我在過程中曾經質疑過…
‎你的能力
‎我誠心向你致歉
‎謝謝，上尉
‎我怎能與這些人交涉這麼多年？
‎我把他們當作一家人
‎殊不知他們有這麼大的痛苦
‎上校，是他們刻意隱瞞的
‎是我失職了，居然沒發現
‎我猜亞提莫斯殺了貝林傑先生
‎是為了防止他通報警方
‎而斯達德先生因不想遇害而逃跑了
‎這麼想沒錯
‎蘭道
‎你已完成了你的職務
‎我在此解除你的合約
‎希望你對此結果很滿意
‎至少希望你能接受我們的謝意
‎希望華府的參議員
‎會打消關閉軍校的念頭
‎我們應該還能死前掙扎一段時間
‎是的，上校
‎你看起來恢復得完好如初
‎我知道令嬡的事
‎好吧
‎小瑪跟這件事有何關係？
‎關係可大了
‎你也知道
‎我是在睡夢中頓悟的
‎李洛弗萊手中的字條
‎把那可憐的傢伙引出營房的字條
‎你把它交給我，著實大意了
‎這是你留給我的字條
‎記得嗎？
‎你的字跡
‎令我大吃一驚
‎大寫和小寫一樣能讓人露出馬腳
‎你寫的字母A、R、G和E
‎跟李洛弗萊手中的字條如出一轍
‎可想而知，我震驚不已
‎這兩張字條可能出自
‎同一個人之手嗎？
‎而且蘭道為何要聯繫李洛弗萊？
‎所幸，我遇到了美妙的派希
‎她把緣由都告訴我了
‎她從軍校舞會返家的路上…
‎抓住她
‎-壓住她
‎-不要
‎你的小瑪遭強暴…
‎不要！
‎…被三名惡棍丟在路上，命若懸絲
‎別出聲
‎朱利斯，抓住她的腿
‎-不要
‎-抓住她
‎-張開她的腿，壓住她
‎-不
‎-求求你
‎-別讓她亂動
‎果然是壞朋友
‎正如李洛弗萊所說
‎小瑪？
‎天啊，小瑪
‎天啊，過來
‎小瑪
‎對不起
‎-對不起
‎-沒關係
‎不會有事的
‎事情會好轉的
‎小瑪，他幫不了妳
‎親愛的，拜託，讓我幫妳
‎但她沒有離家，對吧？
‎小瑪？
‎小瑪
‎小瑪，拜託，過來
‎親愛的，求求妳，過來，拜託
‎不要
‎不會有事的
‎拜託，小瑪，回來
‎事情會好轉的
‎不要
‎我愛你
‎你為何從沒告訴我？
‎這不是
‎我喜歡分享的故事
‎但我原本可以寬慰你
‎幫助你，正如你幫助我一樣
‎這件事恐怕沒人能為我帶來寬慰
‎於是我做了什麼？
‎跟你會做的一樣
‎檢視所有推論
‎兩方人馬在同一晚
‎鎖定同一名學員的機率多大？
‎不大
‎微乎其微
‎除非一方偶然遇到了另一方
‎也許一方，也就是說亞提莫斯和麗雅
‎只想找一具屍體
‎而機會突然出現了
‎他們不在乎屍體的身分
‎只要有心臟就好
‎但他們絕對不敢殺人
‎不，是另一方有意殺人
‎而且是刻意要殺此人
‎為何？
‎蘭道，會不會是為了報復？
‎派希？
‎-救命
‎-你的同夥是誰？
‎有人在嗎？
‎有人嗎？
‎於是，凶手被打斷了
‎但他的目的已達成
‎並悄悄返回他在巴特莫鎮的農舍
‎沒有被任何人發現
‎但他萬萬沒想到自己隔天被召回西點
‎而且得知死者的屍體
‎竟遭人嚴重肢解
‎這完美掩飾了他的罪行
‎彷彿受到了上帝的保佑
‎被指派調查他自己犯下的命案
‎到頭來，亞提莫斯和麗雅
‎將永遠被視為殺人犯
‎沒有所謂的永遠
‎他們會遭遺忘，正如我們所有人一樣
‎我不會遺忘他們
‎尤其是我的麗雅
‎她原本能成為人妻，蘭道
‎成為一個母親
‎我也不會忘記
‎你是如何把我們當傻瓜玩弄
‎傻瓜
‎而我是最傻的一個
‎-不是嗎？
‎-不
‎我一直都打算向你自首
‎我從第一次見到你的那一刻就知道了
‎結果不出所料
‎我…
‎若你想要我道歉，就如你所願
‎我不想要你的道歉
‎不，我想要答案
‎你怎麼知道是弗萊強暴小瑪？
‎那些牛羊也是你殺的嗎？
‎-當然是
‎-那貝林傑呢？
‎貝林傑
‎我不得不挖出他的心
‎才能看起來像是撒旦崇拜者所為
‎對我這老頭子來說
‎可不是容易的差事
‎你怎麼知道貝林傑也有涉案？
‎弗萊的日記
‎貝林傑也認罪了嗎？
‎-有的，我逼他招供
‎-住手，拜託
‎還有誰跟你們一起？
‎朱利斯斯達德
‎朱利斯
‎對不起
‎他們都…
‎他們都記得她的名字
‎我也確保他記得她當時穿的衣服
‎一個細節也不放過
‎只不過斯達德似乎逃過了你的私刑
‎我沒有力氣或意志追殺他
‎我只希望…
‎他下半輩子都會活在恐懼之中
‎他們的惡行令人髮指
‎但你大可以去找塞耶，逼他們認罪
‎我不要他們認罪
‎我要他們死
‎那現在呢？
‎現在？
‎一切由你決定
‎我有兩張字條
‎能送你上絞架
‎好吧
‎埃德加，我時常但願
‎我的小瑪能在舞會那天
‎遇見你
‎誰知道呢？
‎我們可能真會成為一家人
‎我很珍惜…
‎我們的…
‎蘭道，再見了
‎吾愛，安息吧
‎（改編自路易斯拜亞德之著作）